<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>doradolive</title>
  
  
  <link href="https://olivezq.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://olivezq.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2021-12-25T03:34:57.358Z</updated>
  <id>https://olivezq.github.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Olivezq</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>My NEC DR Experience</title>
    <link href="https://olivezq.github.io/2021/12/25/My-NEC-DR-Experience/"/>
    <id>https://olivezq.github.io/2021/12/25/My-NEC-DR-Experience/</id>
    <published>2021-12-25T03:28:03.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-12-25T03:34:57.358Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My NEC DR Experience</p><h2 id="Winter-Vocation"><a href="#Winter-Vocation" class="headerlink" title="Winter Vocation"></a>Winter Vocation</h2><p>The story began before I go to high school.<br>By accident, I met one of my new classmates who became our team leader in the end, and soon agreed to join his NEC team. At that time, I thought this was only one of the common things that I have to experience during high school, but I was wrong. It clearly brought me unique practical knowledge and feelings that no other incident can.</p><h2 id="Lessons"><a href="#Lessons" class="headerlink" title="Lessons"></a>Lessons</h2><p>NEC,  short for National Economics Competition, is divided into three levels to choose from. The easiest level, suitable for PAL students like us, is called PRE. For students in AS and A2, they are asked to take higher levels, DR and AS, while AS the most difficult.<br>Sonic, our leader, told us that his teacher advised him to compete DR. I was surprised at first because we had never studied Economics before, but I still accepted that option without giving it much thought.<br>We soon regret. Everyone else in PAL signed for PRE and people who would compete with us were all from higher grades. But with much courage, we decided to try our best.<br>Well, <em>he who knows not fears not.</em><br>To catch up our Economics, we attended several NEC courses outside school. We also joined our school’s Economics Club to receive further education.<br>I always remember those nights. When everyone got their schoolbags and left the classroom, the three of us would travel far away to a plaza to study Economics, Sonic, Kevin and me. Crowded in a small room, where we learn about absolute advantages, tariffs, quotas, inflation and things like that. We learned both micro and macro at the same time, sometimes even international and current events, because we didn’t have time left.<br>Those nights, after the lesson, I would leaned against the bus’s window, watching the streetlights passing. Thinking about the future which seemed to be so unclear.</p><h2 id="The-Preliminary-Test"><a href="#The-Preliminary-Test" class="headerlink" title="The Preliminary Test"></a>The Preliminary Test</h2><p>We found the fourth teammate online. After all the preparation, the test was imminent, and we were more nervous than ever before.<br>I double checked my computer’s camera which was working well and spent the whole Saturday and Sunday preparinng. Before the competition, my teammates sent several encouraging messages both to me and in the group which was touching.<br>The test ended like it was no more than a normal test. Then we had another week waiting for our results anxiously.</p><h2 id="Results"><a href="#Results" class="headerlink" title="Results"></a>Results</h2><p>“Is the results coming out today?” I asked.<br>Getting an affirmative answer, I took a deep breath.<br>In the afternoon, when I was working on my GitHub, Sonic texted me in an urgent tone. Then I clicked on the “Bloom” icon, and saw the Chinese characters of “rise in rank”, red and big.<br>It took me a while to realize what had just happended. I then thousands checked the results, clicking the “see results” icon again and again. My teammates exclaimed their joy in almost every social media, and the next few hours my computer was busy in replying congradulation messages.<br>It was so unbelievable. So, so, so, unbelievable.<br>We competed with people older than us, and we managed to win out more than a half of them. All beacause of our supportive parents, our respected teachers, and every hardworking member in our team.<br>Our next stop would be Changsha, Hunan in March.<br>And I think, the future is bright.<br><em>Boom like a TNT.</em><br>As Sonic claimed in our group’s description.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">competing NEC DR as PAL</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Life" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/categories/Life/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Economics" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Economics/"/>
    
    <category term="NEC" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/NEC/"/>
    
    <category term="Experience" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Experience/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>good morning my honor</title>
    <link href="https://olivezq.github.io/2021/12/24/demo/"/>
    <id>https://olivezq.github.io/2021/12/24/demo/</id>
    <published>2021-12-24T02:47:40.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-12-24T05:58:33.655Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yet this is a test.<br>GOOD MORNING MY HONOR!</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">this is a test</summary>
    
    
    
    
    <category term="demo" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/demo/"/>
    
    <category term="测试" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/%E6%B5%8B%E8%AF%95/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
