<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>doradolive</title>
  
  
  <link href="https://olivezq.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://olivezq.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2023-06-23T12:58:50.173Z</updated>
  <id>https://olivezq.github.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Olivezq</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Records of June 20th to June 23th</title>
    <link href="https://olivezq.github.io/2023/06/23/Recordoftoday/"/>
    <id>https://olivezq.github.io/2023/06/23/Recordoftoday/</id>
    <published>2023-06-23T12:56:15.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-23T12:58:50.173Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a review because I have been very busy these past few days and I think it’s worth noting.</p><p>June 20th:</p><p>This day, I edited my and Lucy’s volunteer certificates and successfully sent them to Ms.Helen after returning home at night. I originally planned to make a club display board at night, but my drawing skills were limited, and I remembered the display board looked in good condition (the next day when I showed it with Lucy, it was true that many things had already been posted on the display board last year).</p><p>I still need to prepare for the club experience class on the 22nd. Mr.Jacky said that my club sounds very innovative. My club is the Linguistics and Reasoning Club founded by me this year, and indeed, most people do not understand why linguistics and reasoning should be put together. In fact, in the IOLC question (which is a linguistic competition), you will see a row of words from unfamiliar languages and a row of Chinese translations. Translation and the original text are disrupted, so your task is to match the translation with the words. It’s like you come to a crime scene, where there are chaotic clues, and your task is to associate the clues with the characters, restore the case, that is, translate it into the story of the incident. So there is still some relationship between linguistics and inference in the IOLC question. The purpose of my club is to help you better solve cases, help you find the logic in the clues, and more easily and systematically turn the unknown into the known. Through the IOLC questions, learn about different languages and the systematic knowledge behind them.</p><p>I did a PPT for a while tonight, but I haven’t had any ideas about what activities to do for the club experience. So I asked another founder of IOLC in Nanjing Foreign Language School, who said that we could speak Klingon and so on. I actively adopted it. Meanwhile, because Andy, from grade 10, had to take a grammar exam the next day, we moved the rehearsal to noon on the 22nd instead of the 21st. Andy is the next president of my club, even though he is going to the United States next year.</p><p>I am also struggling with what novel to read. Because I realized that I had completely lost interest in novels. I even prefer to watch the seventh edition of Environmental Economics and watch the arguments between ecological economists and neoclassical economists. For novels, I have almost understood their routines and feel absurd and absurd about some plots. In my opinion, some cultures are going backwards.</p><p>That day, my adopted feral cat (which almost turned our house into a restaurant and hotel) brought back a sparrow. The sparrow was very small, frightened, but still alive. My mother gave it some egg yolk to eat, but it ate very little.</p><p>In the evening, I watched my favorite youtuber’s live broadcast for a while while eating instant noodles. This used to be a kind of enjoyment, but that day I found live streaming uninteresting. I always find it interesting. I think many of my entertainment thresholds have reached their peak.</p><p>June 21st:</p><p>This day I unfortunately didn’t succeeded in opening the front door of our class, because the door lock was fixed the day before.</p><p>I have always wanted to preview, but I don’t have time. I think it’s too troublesome. At present, I have already previewed one lesson for each subject, and there seems to be a hope of completing all the previews before summer vacation because I am no longer interested in entertainment.</p><p>At noon, I originally planned to put up a display board, but because I didn’t draw anything worth pasting the day before, this plan was scrapped that day. I also read more than ten IELTS speaking questions, which provided great help for my oral mock exam on the 23rd. I have prepared for every question the teacher took.</p><p>I read the seventh edition of Environmental Economics for a while. This book has become my favorite. That day, I learned about the competition for positions that has the same meaning as Nei Juan (I was shocked by the name, which is actually Nei Juan’s professional term, but no one has ever mentioned it). Although it is rare to see ecological economists arguing with neoclassical economists now in current chapters, it is still very interesting.</p><p>This is my last day of class at school. The next few days will be holidays, professional experiences, volunteering, agricultural studies, and other activities unrelated to learning.</p><p>I saw someone roast about a novel on the Internet, so I decided to read it. I have always liked to see something beyond cognition. These authors always unintentionally lead Magic realism by several universes. I think it happens that this one in my nervous system is different from others.<br>At noon, I was bored and drawing on the inside of my school uniform. Because it was the last day, Lucy and I decided to make an exception to order takeout, so we had Omurice for lunch.</p><p>In the evening, I had a voice chat with Lawrence and Vincent. But because there was a club experience class the next day, I chatted for a while before exiting and began preparing PPTs and lecture notes. I also got a professional experience going to the subway company, which is a school event.</p><p>Tomorrow is Dragon Boat Festival. Everyone has a holiday. I’m still writing the PPT.</p><p>Andy and I have been preparing for the experience class until 11 o’clock.</p><p>June 22nd:</p><p>I slept until 10 o’clock. Arrive at school at 12:30 and sit with Andy in the public lounge for a brief rehearsal. Everyone is beating drums and gongs to prepare for the experience day. When Steven passed by, he said that our club has many people signing up, and I said yes. Originally, Mr.Jacky arranged a regular classroom for us, but he was shocked when he saw that there were 67 people registered for our club. I was also shocked. So he urgently changed the classroom and I went to a large lecture hall. The Moot court has 38 people. I really don’t understand why so many people in our club have signed up.</p><p>Seeing a sentence from “The Crocodile Diary”, “Only healthy people are qualified to fall in love, and using love to treat illness will only make you sicker.” It’s amazing that an author who writes about mental illness cured by falling in love actually likes the author of “The Crocodile Diary”, which makes people wonder if she has really read this book seriously. This is another interesting thing that I have gained entertainment from.</p><p>I need to print 70 manuscripts for the club, so I went up to the third floor to print the materials. Mr.Tracy and Mr.Nathan are both on it, and Ms.Quan is also waiting for printing. I think everyone is really too busy today. The printer broke midway, and Mr.Tracy took half a day to fix it, but fortunately it was fixed. Looking at the parents and students coming in one by one outside the window, I feel like I have today too. The year before last, I came to visit, but this year, it’s I who led the way.</p><p>I was a bit nervous during the club class, and many cameras came in midway.</p><p>Fortunately, there were only 40 minutes left. After speaking, I went home.</p><p>After the club class, I am glad that some students find our club very interesting. I invited a student to write an experience for us, and it turned out that he and I are from the same middle school.</p><p>I discovered a new bad soap opera at night. This makes me very happy.</p><p>On June 23rd:</p><p>I woke up at 9 am to prepare for the IELTS speaking test. Fortunately, I wasn’t asked any questions that I wasn’t prepared for.</p><p>Afterwards, I made an agricultural study map based on the school’s distribution of study agriculture matters. I wrote down all the precautions and so on on on a piece of paper, and after writing it, I almost remembered everything. I am someone who likes to plan things in detail in advance. I don’t like the uncertainty of the future, as it will reduce the number of unexpected events in the future. Understanding life in advance will not make me feel too confused.</p><p>I played a game for a while at noon, but I didn’t think it was interesting.</p><p>Next, as you can see, I am writing my review.</p><p>And I suspect this is all of my past four days. I didn’t study much because I was busy doing my extra curriculum activities. So it’s worth recording.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">This is a review because I have been very busy these past few days and I think it&#39;s worth noting.</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Life" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/categories/Life/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Experience" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Experience/"/>
    
    <category term="Summary" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Summary/"/>
    
    <category term="Record" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Record/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Causes of the SVB Collapse and the Responsibility of FED for This</title>
    <link href="https://olivezq.github.io/2023/04/12/Causes-of-the-SVB-Collapse/"/>
    <id>https://olivezq.github.io/2023/04/12/Causes-of-the-SVB-Collapse/</id>
    <published>2023-04-12T07:49:58.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-04-12T08:02:08.763Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It is believed that Silicon Valley Bank(SVB) itself, regulations on banks and the Federal Reserve Board(FED) caused the collapse of SVB, and FED played a necessary role in this crisis.<br>SVB announced a $1.8 billion loss on March 8th, and it had been losing money in the previous years due to an aggressive series of interest rate hikes at FED, the next day the shares fell 60% by distressed investors. Finally on March 12th, the Silicon Valley Bank crushed after facing increasing financial risks. The FED then announced an emergency lending program to cover the deposits at issue and restore wider confidence in the financial system.[1]<br>There were several reasons for the collapse of SVB, and the decreasing assets and rising debts are parts of the consequences caused by SVB itself. Due to securities and government bonds and aggressive interest rate hikes at FED, the price of bond in SVB was falling. Although this was because of the regulations in the US, it was still inevitable to note that the loss was unrealized and so missed the opportunity to close the loopholes for SVB. In addition, the depositors were also withdrawing money due to anxiety and worries about the bank, lowering the bank savings and resulting in more debts and a larger gap between bank savings and bonds.<br>Regulations were also to be blamed for the close of SVB. When regulations were newly in place after the 2008 Global Financial Crisis, they were suitable for the financial system because they were designed to tackle the economic problems at that time. However, as time changes, the financial system alters too, so the regulations may become out of date and can not adapt the situation nowadays. This provided loopholes for banks and the SVB collapsed as constant dripping wears away a stone.<br>The collapse of SVB was also caused by FED, both its interest rates and responses. As FED increased the interest rates, it brought unintended consequences such as the loss on the sale of securities including the Treasury and mortgage bonds in SVB. Since there was loss, investors dumped SVB bank shares due to fears which brought systemic risks for SVB. The FED did not make responses to these risks in advanced, and could only reassure depositors and use lending facilities in order to protect them which may bring moral hazard.<br>The carelessness of SVB was a major cause of the collapse of itself, however, it is FED that increased the interest rates which made SVB have the chance of leading to failing. The polices of the Fed was the main trigger, and without its measures, SVB could not have failed due to its own negligence. So although it is doubtful to completely blame the FED for all of this, it played a necessary role in this crisis.<br>In conclusion, It is thought that SVB itself, regulations of banks, and the FED led to the collapse of SVB, and the Federal Reserve had a noteworthy responsibility for this.</p><h1 id="References"><a href="#References" class="headerlink" title="References:"></a>References:</h1><p>[1]<a href="https://abcnews.go.com/Business/timeline-silicon-valley-bank-collapse/story?id=97846565">https://abcnews.go.com/Business/timeline-silicon-valley-bank-collapse/story?id=97846565</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">It is believed that Silicon Valley Bank(SVB) itself, regulations on banks and the Federal Reserve Board(FED) caused the collapse of SVB, and FED played a necessary role in this crisis.</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Rationality" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/categories/Rationality/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Writing" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Writing/"/>
    
    <category term="Economics" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Economics/"/>
    
    <category term="Essay" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Essay/"/>
    
    <category term="US" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/US/"/>
    
    <category term="FED" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/FED/"/>
    
    <category term="SVB" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/SVB/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Cheerilee</title>
    <link href="https://olivezq.github.io/2023/03/28/Cheerilee/"/>
    <id>https://olivezq.github.io/2023/03/28/Cheerilee/</id>
    <published>2023-03-28T13:08:30.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-03-29T10:28:09.874Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A/N: This will be in Chinese, since they were written in Chinese when I was in secondary school. The characters belong to <em>My Little Pony</em> and its fan-fiction <em>Cheerilee’s Garden</em>. This is a fan-fiction of <em>Cheerilee’s Garden</em>. This includes two chapters, which I wrote separately. Both chapters were using two of our texts in our textbook for preference.</p><h1 id="Chapter-1-车厘子的花园"><a href="#Chapter-1-车厘子的花园" class="headerlink" title="Chapter 1 车厘子的花园"></a>Chapter 1 车厘子的花园</h1><p>车厘子离开镇子已四年有余，她最不能忘记的是她的花园。</p><p>四年前的春天，祖母死了，学生们在一场大火中丧生，正是祸不单行的日子。她从失火的剧院到家中，打算摘几朵她精心培育的花去奔丧。走到花园，看见满院的狼藉，想起祖母，不禁簌簌地流下眼泪。祖母曾说，“事已如此，不必难过，好在天无绝人之路！”  </p><p>回学校接受记者采访，车厘子只顾流泪；又支支吾吾地不知道在说什么。那些日子，学校中光景很是惨淡，一半为了丧事，一半为了学员的短缺。丧事完毕，车厘子应校长的要求回到家中休息。  </p><p>车厘子是火灾中唯一的幸存者。火灾发生在剧院，她当时是一部剧的指导老师。学生们的每一句台词，每一个动作都有她的指点。她在台下看着这群小孩子们，心里很欣慰。演出大获成功后，她在处理私事，孩子们都在幕后欢声笑语。不知从哪，突然窜出了一团火焰，她在高温的剧院内，听到一个人的声音，出于求生的本能，她冲破了窗玻璃，却没能再见到可爱的学生们。有几位家长冲进还在燃烧的剧院中，即便如此，生还者中也没有看到任何一个孩子的身影。  </p><p>在此之前，车厘子曾带着孩子们来到她的花园。前途无量的孩子们还没上小学，一个个都扬着童稚的脸庞。要教的太多了，得把整块黑板从门中移过来，才可在这块土地上开讲。孩子们便又忙着搬黑板。车厘子当时正好腿有些伤，坐在轮椅上。她那时真是聪明过分，总觉他们搬地不大利索，非自己插嘴不可。但他们终于通过了后门，就把黑板立在地上。他们给她拣定了最中间的一个位置；她抖抖她的毯子，那上面有学生搬黑板身上落下的粉笔灰。讲到历史时，她心里暗笑他们的迂；他们没有亲历过，教他们只是白教！而且他们这样小的人，长大了还能记得什么？唉，她现在想想，那时真是太自负了！  </p><p>有一天，她对最喜欢她的一位学生说道，“小萍花，下课了。”小萍花望外面看了看，说，“我送我家的几个苹果给你。你就在此地，不要走动。”车厘子看花园的栅栏外有几个卖东西的等着顾客。走到那边苹果公社的摊子，须越过花园和栅栏。小萍花虽是农村出生，刚开始和大人干农活也不是很方便。车厘子本来要作罢的，小萍花不肯，只好让她去。她看见她戴着和同学一起做的友谊手链，穿着社团的衣服，鞋上还有泥巴，慢慢地走到后门，慢慢探身下去，尚不大难。可是她穿过花丛，爬上那边栅栏，就不容易了。她用两手扒开花朵，两脚注意着不被玫瑰刺扎到；她瘦小的身子弓着，显出努力的样子。这时车厘子看见小萍花的背影，她的泪很快地流下来了。她赶紧拭干了泪，怕小萍花看见，也怕别人看见。她再向外看时，学生已抱了红彤彤的苹果望回走了。过花丛时，她先将苹果高举在头顶，自己慢慢寻找没有花的地方踩，再继续向前走。到门口时，腿脚不便的车厘子赶紧去搀她。小萍花和车厘子走到室内，将苹果一股脑儿放在桌子上。于是扑扑衣上的泥土，心里很轻松似的，过一会说，“老师，我一点也没有踩到你的花朵，也没有伤到自己呢！”她的话中带着一点乡人的口音。车厘子望着她走出去。她走了几步，回过头看见老师，说，“老师你快吃苹果呀。”等她的背影混入来来往往的人里，再找不着了，车厘子便进来坐下，她的眼泪又来了。  </p><p>近几年来，她辞去了老师的职务，踏上了旅途，心却是越走越紧。她少年背井离乡，做了许多大事。那知老境却如此颓唐！四年过去，花园跟着房子卖了，她也没了牵挂。此时抬头瞥见一丛玫瑰花，她终于又开始回想起旧事。时光似乎停留在了那一届，她只是惦记着她的花园，惦记着她的学生。提笔想写信，却绕不过四年前的那把火。小萍花的姐姐在大众传言是车厘子纵的火时，也曾写了一信给她，信中说道，“我的妹妹生前除了她的奶奶，最爱的就是你。我相信你，从她的描述来看，你不是个杀人犯。”她读到此处，在晶莹的泪光中，又看见那瘦小的，衣裳单薄的，鞋上有泥的背影。唉！她不知何时再能与学生们在午后花园相见！</p><h1 id="Chapter-2-车厘子与失火剧院"><a href="#Chapter-2-车厘子与失火剧院" class="headerlink" title="Chapter 2 车厘子与失火剧院"></a>Chapter 2 车厘子与失火剧院</h1><p>车厘子老师，已经说过，是一个隔壁班的全职老师，说得具体一点，就是隔壁班的班主任。我的朋友小萍花和许多别的人都这样称呼她，似乎略带些敬畏的意思。只有她自己叫她车厘子。我平时叫她“老师”，连“车”字也不带；但到十分感激她的时候，例如知道了小时候教我历史的却是她的时候，就叫她车厘子老师。</p><p>我们那里没有名字只有一个单词的；她眼瞳是翠绿翠绿的，“车厘子”也不是形容词。又不是她的名字，记得她没提过，我们也没听说过她的真名。记得她也曾告诉过我这个名称的来历：她生下来之时，屁股上有三朵车厘子花，那就是胎记。后来她有了真正的名字了，小时候车厘子的昵称大家早就叫惯了，没有再改口，于是她从此也就成为车厘子老师了。</p><p>虽然背地里说人长短不是好事情，但倘使要我说句真心话，我可只得说：我实在佩服她。我在隔壁班里最讨厌的是絮絮叨叨的提亚拉了，一会那个不行，这个不行的，还超有优越感，别人还在精疲力竭地干什么事，她倒在旁边把鼻子抬地高高的，指指点点。隔壁班里一有些小风波，不知怎的我总疑心和这“优越感”有些关系。一到春游之类的活动，搭帐篷时她又倒双手灵活了起来，在草坪中间摆一个超级大的帐篷，挤得其他人没有余地搭了，久围在草坪和小河的边缘上，又已经累得不想花时间注意会不会掉河里去了，可谁也不愿意睡着睡着突然淋一身水。拍她帐篷呢，不动；叫她呢，也不闻。</p><p>车厘子听到我们多回诉苦之后，曾经敲过帐篷的链子。我也知道这意思是要提亚拉多给我们一些空席。她不开口。但到夜里，我被小萍花拍醒的时候，却看见草坪上骤然出现了一片光溜溜的土地。我想，这实在是做梦也不敢想的事情了。车厘子老师可真是厉害得要命。 </p><p>她还懂得许多规矩；这些规矩，也大概是我所最值得学习的。一天中最高兴的时节，自然要数和同学一起去食堂吃午饭了。一般来说，班主任带着我们下了楼，就可以自己去吃饭了。然而一天她进来带我们班吃饭，却带着我们一直向食堂走了。</p><p>“同学们，你们牢牢记住!”她极其郑重地说。“跑地越快，越早吃饭，记得了么?学习也是这样。不要只顾着说话，忘了咕咕叫的肚子。”她又跑起来了，“不然，到了最后，你只能吃别人的剩饭了……。”大家都开始进食堂了，她却立刻伸出臂膊，拉开门口的帘子，好省我们一点麻烦。我惊异地看她时，只见她微笑着看着我。</p><p>“老师，谢谢……”</p><p>“哪里哪里，不客气。”她于是十分喜欢似的，笑将起来。这可真是奇了怪了，这么体贴、以身作则的好老师，怎会教出排名倒数第一的班级呢？恐怕是隔壁班太顽皮了罢，就喜欢欺负这种老师。</p><p>但当我对她产生敬意的时候，一面又在羡慕着车厘子老师的花园了。这羡慕是从小萍花惹起来的。她是车厘子班的，性格大胆，做什么事都不怕的，还经常把自己家种的苹果偷偷送给我们。她的姐姐却正相反，特别诚实守信，从这座山到那座山，把自己的土地耕地好好的，从不占一丝一毫他人的地的便宜。小萍花说，车厘子老师的花园里，有着蛋黄的风信子，雪白的丁香，火红的山茶，闻起来香甜的铃兰，长满刺的红玫瑰……</p><p>我很愿意看看这样的花朵，但不好意思力逼小萍花有事没事带我去看，她是很疏懒的。问别人呢，谁也不肯真实地回答我。车厘子的后花园离我家还特别远，步行的话要走1个小时，还不知道能不能看到正盛开着的花。 </p><p>玩的时候倒是没有什么的，但一坐下，我就记得车厘子老师的花园。</p><p>有一天终于忍不住了，想着怎么也要去看看小萍花说的那神奇的花园，放学背上书包就往车厘子家的大概方向冲过去。等到到了她家后，早就累得靠在旁边的柱子上。眼皮挣扎着抬起来，去瞅瞅那花园。</p><p>我似乎遇着了一个霹雳，全体都震悚起来；赶紧去看，曾经车厘子精心养护而鸟语花香的花园如今破败不堪。藤蔓和杂草淹没了花园过去的美好，花朵在它们的挤压下窒息、凋亡。</p><p>我一抬头，看到车厘子在客厅里不停地来回踱着步。木头碎渣一直从客厅的桌子旁延伸到厨房，只要稍稍看看就会明白其中一条桌腿发生了什么。陶瓷的碎渣和已经干硬的泥土散落一地，这像是被飓风来回蹂躏过的惨象。她停顿了片刻，随后又把目光移到那些幸存的家具上面。我立刻趴了下来。  </p><p>“为什么！我为什么不能让那些小孩们守规矩！”她疯狂地吼叫着。  </p><p>我仔细想了一下，这个问题对她来说事实上相当严重。她一直能带出最好的学生，怀着满满的期待看着她们成长为可爱的花朵。然而这一次，竟然有这么多的孩子，在成为她的学生后漫长的六个月的时间里，什么也没学会，半个字也没有！  </p><p>这使我发生害怕了，她曾经在图书馆里不分昼夜地呆了数天，借口学习那些关于如何激发学生兴趣的材料。我突然明白，这不是她真正的目的，真正的原因是横亘在她心头的疑问。</p><p>“不！”我听到车厘子尖叫着踢向镜子，镜中的车厘子瞬间碎裂成千片，散落于地。</p><p>几分钟过去了，我还是趴在地上，一动也不敢动。突然听到了一声清冽的有什么东西划过桌子的声音，还挺大声的。</p><p>“我想…”她在黑暗中呢喃着，然后拿起了刀，把它放在惨白的月色下端详。我趴地更低了。“是时候再来一场演出了…”  </p><p>她咯咯地笑了起来，将恐惧、疑虑以及其他黑暗的情绪卷入了疯狂地漩涡。她拿起身边的一张照片——一张就在这个月初照的照片：每年都有的惯例‘老师和学生们的合影’。她把照片从相框里取出，然后在客厅里点了一根蜡烛，她竟然还找得到一只不太残破的蜡烛。当昏暗的火光照亮了屋子，她小心地把照片放入火焰，任由火舌从蹄开始舔舐着影像被留在了相片上的小孩们。  </p><p>六个月来，车厘子第一次笑的如此开心。</p><p>我那天晚上回到家时，已经是凌晨三点了。几个月后，镇上的剧院失火了。小萍花和她的同学们都在那里面，车厘子是唯一的幸存者。</p><p>灾难已经过去了几周，在这几周之间，发生了很多事情。他们对这场灾难的起因做了很多调查，但火灾以及那之后的大水摧毁了一切，调查员们已经无法从那片废墟之中找出哪怕一点点的线索。 </p><p>每当车厘子被问及此事，她总是流露出悲痛、迷茫的神态，她声称当灾难发生时，她正在剧院的另一侧处理其他的事物。尽管有人质疑这究竟算不算是一种过失，但政府最后并没有对车厘子提起诉讼。  </p><p>清扫工作已经持续了整整一星期，但建筑的碎片依然散布在地上。在灾难后的周末里，举办了一场为所有在火灾中遇难的小孩们共同的葬礼，因为已经找不到她们的尸体，她们的棺木里放置的仅仅是一些石块以及死者生前使用的物件。葬礼上，所有的人都沉浸在悲伤的气氛里，其中包括车厘子，那个流着喜悦的眼泪的女人，她强忍着自己的感情，终于捱到了葬礼的最后。很多人经过她的身边，留下一句句“节哀”、“一切都会过去的”或者“这不怪你”之类的安慰。</p><p>两周之后。我路过车厘子的花园。  </p><p>车厘子在太阳下大汗淋漓地小声言语。在这个艳阳高照的早上，太阳晒的她皮肤灼痛，但她毫不在意。终于，她做完了工作。  </p><p>“我，车厘子，永远不会让杂草侵染我的花园，再也不会。”</p><p>这句话，乃是每天在我梦里萦绕的，最可怕的那句话。 当然，一切都没被证实，而且除了我外没有人会存在那样的猜想。但仍然有可能，杀害我最好朋友小萍花的凶手就站在花园里，就在那里呆着，就在那！</p><p>小萍花的老师，车厘子，辞了这人世，大概也有了几年了罢。我终于不知道她的姓名，她的经历。 </p><p>胆小可悲的我呵，就连注视车厘子的眼睛的勇气都没有！</p><p>四月十一日</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Two chapters I wrote in Chinese during secondary school which were my essays turned in to my teacher.</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Life" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/categories/Life/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Writing" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Writing/"/>
    
    <category term="Fiction" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Fiction/"/>
    
    <category term="Fan-fiction" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Fan-fiction/"/>
    
    <category term="Fabricate" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Fabricate/"/>
    
    <category term="Characters" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Characters/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Speeches Topics</title>
    <link href="https://olivezq.github.io/2023/03/10/Speeches-Topic/"/>
    <id>https://olivezq.github.io/2023/03/10/Speeches-Topic/</id>
    <published>2023-03-10T12:06:11.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-03-10T12:29:27.133Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Topic-1"><a href="#Topic-1" class="headerlink" title="Topic 1"></a>Topic 1</h1><h2 id="Introduce-the-Chinese-Education-system-to-your-foreign-friend-What-are-its-advantages"><a href="#Introduce-the-Chinese-Education-system-to-your-foreign-friend-What-are-its-advantages" class="headerlink" title="Introduce the Chinese Education system to your foreign friend. What are its advantages?"></a>Introduce the Chinese Education system to your foreign friend. What are its advantages?</h2><p>The Chinese education system is divided into three parts: primary, secondary, and higher education. Primary education is compulsory in China, and all children between the ages of 6 and 15 are required to attend school. This period lasts for nine years and is divided into two stages: six years of primary school and three years of middle school.</p><p>Secondary education is divided into three levels: junior high school (three years), senior high school (three years), and vocational school (two to four years). Students must take and pass the National College Entrance Examination (NCEE) in order to enter a university or college.</p><p>Higher education in China is divided into undergraduate and graduate programs. Undergraduate programs are four years in length, while graduate programs can range from two to six years. Students must have a bachelor’s degree in order to enter a graduate program.</p><p>In addition to this, there are also numerous private schools, language schools, and international schools in China. These schools have their own educational systems and are often tailored to the needs of their students.</p><p>The Chinese education system is one of the oldest and most respected in the world. It is well-known for its emphasis on academic excellence and the importance of hard work and self-discipline. Students are taught to think critically and to develop problem-solving skills. At the same time, they learn the value of cooperation and teamwork.</p><p>The Chinese education system is designed to provide students with the knowledge and skills they need to succeed in their future careers. It is based on high academic standards and a focus on excellence which encourages students to strive for the best possible results. It also teaches critical thinking and problem-solving skills to help students develop the ability to think independently and come up with creative solutions to difficult challenges. Additionally, the system encourages teamwork and cooperation as well as a disciplined and structured work ethic. Finally, it is highly competitive with university entrance exams that select the best students for higher education. Overall, the Chinese education system is an effective way to prepare students for the future.</p><h1 id="Topic-2"><a href="#Topic-2" class="headerlink" title="Topic 2"></a>Topic 2</h1><h2 id="Introduce-to-your-foreign-friend-the-role-technology-plays-in-young-people’s-school-life-and-social-life"><a href="#Introduce-to-your-foreign-friend-the-role-technology-plays-in-young-people’s-school-life-and-social-life" class="headerlink" title="Introduce to your foreign friend the role technology plays in young people’s school life and social life."></a>Introduce to your foreign friend the role technology plays in young people’s school life and social life.</h2><p>Technology plays a huge role in the lives of young people, both in school and in their social lives. In school, technology is used in a variety of ways, from classroom instruction to assignments and assessments. Teachers can use technology to create interactive activities to engage students and provide more personalized learning experiences. Technology can also help students collaborate on projects and connect with peers. Outside of the classroom, technology is often used to stay connected with friends and family. Social media is a popular way for young people to stay in touch with friends, share photos, or just see what’s going on in the world. Technology can also be used to access a variety of entertainment options, from streaming music to watching movies and TV shows. </p><p>Technology also provides a range of educational opportunities for young people. There are online courses and tutorials that can help students learn subjects in more depth or get ahead in their studies. Technology can also be used to access educational resources, such as online libraries, journals, and textbooks. And with the rise of digital communication, young people can now connect with experts from around the world and learn from their experiences. Finally, technology can also help young people explore career options, apply to colleges, and search for jobs, providing them with greater control over their future. In short, technology plays a huge role in the lives of young people, both in school and in their social lives.</p><h1 id="Topic-3"><a href="#Topic-3" class="headerlink" title="Topic 3"></a>Topic 3</h1><h2 id="Describe-to-your-foreign-friend-your-favorite-Chinese-film-director-or-actor"><a href="#Describe-to-your-foreign-friend-your-favorite-Chinese-film-director-or-actor" class="headerlink" title="Describe to your foreign friend your favorite Chinese film, director or actor."></a>Describe to your foreign friend your favorite Chinese film, director or actor.</h2><p>My favorite Chinese actor is Jackie Chan. He is a famous actor, martial artist and stunt performer. He is well-known for his acrobatic fighting style, comic timing, and use of improvised weapons in his movies. He is one of the most recognized and influential cinematic personalities in the world.</p><p>Jackie Chan was born in Hong Kong in 1954. He began his career as a child actor in the 1960s and rose to fame in the 1970s after appearing in the hit movie Snake in the Eagle’s Shadow. He has since starred in over 150 films, including the Rush Hour trilogy, Drunken Master, The Karate Kid, and Rumble in the Bronx. His unique combination of martial arts and comedy has made him a popular action star.</p><p>Jackie Chan has won numerous awards, including the Lifetime Achievement Award from the Hong Kong Film Awards and the Asian Film Award for Outstanding Contribution to Asian Cinema. He has also been honored with a star on the Hollywood Walk of Fame. He is a UNICEF Goodwill Ambassador and a recipient of the Medal of the Order of Australia.</p><p>Jackie Chan is an inspiration to many young aspiring actors. He has shown that it is possible to become successful in the movie industry with hard work and dedication. He has also shown that martial arts and comedy can be combined to create entertaining and exciting films. He continues to be a popular figure in the Chinese film industry and an example of success for many years.</p><h1 id="Topic-4"><a href="#Topic-4" class="headerlink" title="Topic 4"></a>Topic 4</h1><h2 id="Describe-your-favorite-Chinese-musician-or-Chinese-style-of-music-to-your-foreign-friend"><a href="#Describe-your-favorite-Chinese-musician-or-Chinese-style-of-music-to-your-foreign-friend" class="headerlink" title="Describe your favorite Chinese musician or Chinese style of music to your foreign friend."></a>Describe your favorite Chinese musician or Chinese style of music to your foreign friend.</h2><p>My favorite Chinese musician is G.E.M. (also known as Gloria Tang Tsz-kei). She is a singer-songwriter, musician, and actress from Hong Kong. She is known for her powerful vocals, emotional lyrics, and modern take on traditional Chinese music.</p><p>G.E.M. has been making music since 2006 and her style of music incorporates many different genres including pop, R&amp;B, hip-hop, and rock. She has released a number of successful albums and singles, and even won several awards including Best Original Music at the Hong Kong Film Awards in 2011.</p><p>G.E.M. has a unique style of music that blends traditional Chinese music with modern elements. She has been known to incorporate traditional Chinese instruments such as the erhu and guzheng into her music, creating a unique sound. Her lyrics often reflect her personal journey as well as her views on society and the world.</p><p>In terms of traditional Chinese music, one of my favorite styles is called Beijing Opera. Beijing Opera is a type of Chinese opera that combines music, dance, and acrobatics. It is one of the oldest and most influential forms of Chinese musical theatre. The music of Beijing Opera consists of a variety of instruments including drums, cymbals, gongs, and other traditional Chinese instruments.</p><p>Overall, G.E.M. and Beijing Opera are two of my favorite Chinese musicians and styles of music. They both have unique elements that make them stand out, and they both showcase the amazing diversity and creativity of the Chinese music scene.</p><h1 id="Topic-5"><a href="#Topic-5" class="headerlink" title="Topic 5"></a>Topic 5</h1><h2 id="Describe-to-your-foreign-friend-the-most-important-Chinese-value-you-have-learnt-from-home-and-school"><a href="#Describe-to-your-foreign-friend-the-most-important-Chinese-value-you-have-learnt-from-home-and-school" class="headerlink" title="Describe to your foreign friend the most important Chinese value you have learnt from home and school."></a>Describe to your foreign friend the most important Chinese value you have learnt from home and school.</h2><p>The most important Chinese value that I have learnt from home and school is the concept of filial piety. Filial piety is a virtue of respect for one’s parents, elders and ancestors. It is deeply rooted in Chinese culture and has been passed down for centuries.</p><p>In Chinese society, filial piety is seen as one of the most important values and is highly respected. It is believed that by showing respect and obedience to one’s parents and elders, a person can gain virtue and moral character. This is why at home, my parents have always stressed the importance of filial piety. We are taught to always show respect and obey our parents, and to never forget to show our love and care for them.</p><p>At school, we are also taught the importance of filial piety. We are taught to respect our elders and to always remember our parents’ sacrifice and hard work. We are also taught to be kind and generous to others, especially those who are in need.</p><p>Filial piety is an important concept in Chinese culture, and it has taught me to show respect and obedience to my parents and elders. It is also a reminder to always be kind and generous to others, no matter what their social status is. By having this virtue, I have been able to build strong relationships with my family and friends, and have also become a better person in general.</p><h1 id="Conclusion-A-N"><a href="#Conclusion-A-N" class="headerlink" title="Conclusion (A/N)"></a>Conclusion (A/N)</h1><p>I finished preparing all the topics’ speeches before I noticed that I only need to choose one from the 5 topics. I thought this competition was as sick as the Hope Star Competition or FLTRP Cup. You know, when I was in like, fourth grade, I participated in FLTRP Cup, and we were asked to choose randomly from a box and there were Chinese idioms in it, and whatever it was we needed to illustrate what it was in front of the public, which meant we needed to recite all Chinese idioms’ stories that were possibly in the box. However, this competition is kind and it didn’t pushed us to recite all the topics and choose randomly.<br>Thankfully.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">I finished preparing all the topics&#39; speeches before I noticed that I only need to choose one from the 5 topics.</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Life" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/categories/Life/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Practical" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Practical/"/>
    
    <category term="ChatGPT" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/ChatGPT/"/>
    
    <category term="Speech" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Speech/"/>
    
    <category term="Culture" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Culture/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>My Economics Reading List and Thoughts</title>
    <link href="https://olivezq.github.io/2023/02/26/reading%20list/"/>
    <id>https://olivezq.github.io/2023/02/26/reading%20list/</id>
    <published>2023-02-26T07:53:26.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-02-26T08:33:09.897Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So for the last few weeks, I’ve been reading Economics books. Some of them really inspired me a lot. And here’s a joke:<br>I was writing my reading list to hand it in to my counselor. And I said:</p><blockquote><p>The books were really inspiring, I read books like: <em>Nacroeconomics: How to Run A Drug Cartel</em>, and <em>Undercover Economists</em>, <em>Freakonomics: A Rogue Economist Explores</em> which mentioned how criminal rate increases as the government abandoned abortion and how people sell drugs successfully, and <em>Bad Blood</em> which talked about how you lie to the whole Silicon Valley without being caught for almost a decade.</p></blockquote><p>I guess the reading list does look quite weird. But that’s what makes Economics interesting. Actually, I do treat Economics as something like any sniper would treat a gun. I personally call Economics “Sniping”, and this name really motivated me to keep on reading Economics (because I’ve been really keen on becoming a sniper in the future). But that is another story, and today I’m just going to share my feelings and thoughts about what I’ve read.</p><h2 id="Freakonomics-A-Rogue-Economist-Explores"><a href="#Freakonomics-A-Rogue-Economist-Explores" class="headerlink" title="Freakonomics: A Rogue Economist Explores"></a>Freakonomics: A Rogue Economist Explores</h2><p>I read this book in three days, and it was really a great book and was shorter than I thought. It was not like talking about Economics directly, but more like showing how an economist get involved in something that looks rather like Sociology or Criminology.<br>It mentioned many interesting things that are facts but not much people realize them. For example, how you can detect a teacher is cheating for her students, how it is related with Japanese sports, and how you can know the people selling houses to you are lying, how abortion is related to criminal rate while many people state other reasons for increasing criminal rate, and how baby names are related to the baby’s race and its family wealth and education level, and why popular baby names keep changing from time to time. Some sentences and paragraphs in it really made me open my mind.<br>Here are some sentences in this book.</p><blockquote><p>She was a poor, uneducated, unskilled, alcoholic, drug-using twenty-one-year-old woman who had already given up two children for adoption and now, in 1970, found herself pregnant again. But in Texas, as in all but a few states at that time, abortion was illegal.<br>…<br>Decades of studies have shown that a child born into an adverse family environment is far more likely than other children to become a criminal. And the millions of women most likely to have an abortion in the wake of Roe v. Wade–poor, unmarried, and teenage mothers for whom illegal abortion had been too expensive or too hard to get–were often models of adversity. They were the very women whose children, if born, would have been much more likely than average to become criminals.<br>…<br>How many times did they cite legalized abortion as a cause? Zero.<br>…<br>Economics is above all a science of measurement. It comprises an extraordinarily powerful and flexible set of tools that can reliably assess a thicket of information to determine the effect of any one factor, or even the whole effect.<br>…<br>Consider yourself, then, in the company of a third person–or, if you will, a pair of third people–eager to explore the objective merits of interesting cases. These explorations generally begin with the asking of a simple unasked question.<br>…<br>W. C. Fields once said: a thing worth having is a thing worth cheating for.<br>…<br>The secret Klan handshake was a left-handed, limp-wristed fish wiggle. When a traveling Klansman wanted to locate brethren in a strange town, he would ask for a “Mr.Ayak”–”Ayak” being code for “Are you a Klansman?” He would hope to hear this response:”Yes, and I also know a Mr.Akai”–code for “A Klansman Am I.”<br>…<br>He explained the role of Klan officers in any local Klavern: the Klaliff (vice president), Klokard (lecturer), Kludd (chaplain), Kligrapp (secretary), Klabee (treasurer), Kladd (conductor), Klarogo (inner guard), Klexter (outer guard), the Klokann (a five-man investigative committee), and the Klavaliers (whose leader was called Chief Ass Tearer).<br>…<br>Stetson Kennedy continued to relay the Klan secrets obtained by John Brown to other broadcast and print outlets.<br>…<br>Like Stetson Kennedy, they were dealing in information. (Had the Internet been around when Kennedy was attacking the Klan, he probably would have been blogging his brains out.)<br>…<br>As Supreme Court Justice Louis D. Brandeis once wrote, “Sunlight is said to be the best of disinfectants.”<br>…<br>Unlike street crimes, they do not leave behind a corpse or a broken window. Unlike a bagel criminal–that is, someone who eats on of Paul Feldman’s bagels but doesn’t pay–an information criminal typically doesn’t have someone like Feldman tallying every nickel. For an information crime to reach the surface, something drastic must happen. When it does, the results tend to be pretty revealing. The perpetrators, after all, weren’t thinking about their private actions being made public. Consider the “Enron tapes,” the secretly recorded conversations of Enron employees that surfaced after the company imploded.<br>…<br>Armed with information, experts can exert a gigantic, if unspoken, leverage: fear. Fear that your children will find you dead on the bathroom floor of a heart attack if you do not have angioplasty surgery. Fear that a cheap casket will expose your grandmother to a terrible underground fate.<br>…<br>“It ain’t all about killing. They seen these movies and shit, they think it’s all about running around tearing shit up. But it’s not. You’ve got to learn to be part of an organization; you can’t be fighting all the time. It’s bad for business.”<br>…<br>Cocaine was a drug of power and panache. It was clean, it was white, it was pretty. Heroin was droopy and pot was foggy but cocaine provided a beautiful high.<br>…<br>it was also very expensive. Nor did the high last long. This led cocaine users to try jacking up the drug’s potency. They did this primarily by freebasing–adding ammonia and ethyl ether to cocaine hydrochloride, or powdered cocaine, and burning it to free up the “base” cocaine. But this could be dangerous. As more than a few flame-scarred drug users could attest, chemistry is best left to chemists.<br>…<br>By happy coincidence, some of their fellow inmates were gang members with close ties to Colombian drug dealers. In the past, the black gangsters had bought their drugs from a middleman, the Mafia–which, as it happened, was then being pummeled by the federal government’s new anti-racketeering laws. But by the time crack came to Chicago, the black gangsters had made the connections to buy their cocaine directly from Colombian dealers.<br>…<br>Recall for a moment the two boys, one white and one black, who were described in chapter 5. The white boy who grew up outside Chicago had smart, solid, encouraging, loving parents who stressed education and family. The boy from Daytona Beach was abandoned by his mother, was beaten by his father, and had become a full-fledged gangster by his teens. So what became of the two boys? The second child, now twenty-eight years old, is Roland G. Fryer Jr., the Harvard economist studying black underachievement. The while child also made it to Harvard. But soon after, things went badly for him. His name is Ted Kaczynski.</p></blockquote><p>This book reminded me of a fiction I’ve been reading since secondary school: <em>Harry Potter and the Methods of Rationality</em>(hereinafter refer to as <em>HPMOR</em>). It talked about if Harry Potter was a scientist what will he do in the magic world. And he also mentioned many facts and theories that were interesting. For example, this is a short-cut from HPMOR.</p><blockquote><p>“I have a feeling,” Harry said finally, “that we’re coming at this from the wrong angle. There’s a tale I once heard about some students who came into a physics class, and the teacher showed them a large metal plate near a fire. She ordered them to feel the metal plate, and they felt that the metal nearer the fire was cooler and the metal further away was warmer. And she said, write down your guess for why this happens. So some students wrote down ‘because of how the metal conducts heat’, and some students wrote down ‘because of how the air moves’, and on one said ‘this just seems impossible’, and the real answer was that before the students came into the room, the teacher turned the plate around.”</p></blockquote><p><em>Freakonomics</em> is for now my favorite economics book.</p><h2 id="New-Ideas-From-Dead-Economists"><a href="#New-Ideas-From-Dead-Economists" class="headerlink" title="New Ideas From Dead Economists"></a>New Ideas From Dead Economists</h2><p>This is a great book which started from the lives of dead Economists, and analyzed their theories, and concluded the author’s new ideas from them.<br>My favorite parts were the paragraphs where economists in the past had fights together, and there was this ping-pong kind of thing going on with their theories, like Keynes came up with solution A while Milton stated “However” and gave a solution B, and they were like having fights on their newspapers, and a new theory started to form.<br>It is also the book that let me found that I am interested in Economic History. Reading these economists lives is a great enjoyment to me, and those economists also had their own way of treating their lives like they were real lively persons, maybe one is ambitious and one is narrow-minded. And it also mentioned the world’s history background when they were living. For example:</p><blockquote><p>such as the tale of the Japanese, French, and American corporate executives, each sentenced to death. The executioner offers a final request. The Frenchman asks:”I’d like a bottle of cabernet sauvignon and a feast featuring escargot, pheasant, and crème brulée.” The Japanese responds:”I’d like to give a lecture on the merits of Japanese corporate management.” Finally, the American gives his last request: “Would you please kill me before the lecture on Japanese management?”</p></blockquote><p> Such tales are really interesting to know.</p><h2 id="Money-Mischief-Episodes-in-Monetary-History"><a href="#Money-Mischief-Episodes-in-Monetary-History" class="headerlink" title="Money Mischief: Episodes in Monetary History"></a>Money Mischief: Episodes in Monetary History</h2><blockquote><p>Motives and intentions matter far less than the outcome. And, it this as in so many other cases, the outcome was very different from that intended by the well-meaning advocates of the Coinage Act of 1873.</p></blockquote><p>I read this book before I read <em>New Ideas From Dead Economists</em>, so I didn’t know the author Milton when I was reading, and what I read was a total mess. After I read <em>New Ideas From Dead Economists</em>, I finally started to understand what Milton tried to say in <em>Money Mischief</em>. The part that gave me great impression was still about economic history, that is the Coinage Act of 1873. It talked about how people play with silver to increase their money and the exchange rates. I can learn a lot from these brilliant event.<br>Man, watching others controlling money makes me thrill.</p><h2 id="Basic-Economics-A-Citizen’s-Guide-to-the-Economy-Revised-and-Expanded-Version"><a href="#Basic-Economics-A-Citizen’s-Guide-to-the-Economy-Revised-and-Expanded-Version" class="headerlink" title="Basic Economics:A Citizen’s Guide to the Economy(Revised and Expanded Version)"></a>Basic Economics:A Citizen’s Guide to the Economy(Revised and Expanded Version)</h2><p>So, I don’t quite like this book… because it was indeed talking about <em>basic economics</em>, but they were too basic for me. Like I was reading my textbook instead of extra reading.</p><h2 id="The-Undercover-Economist"><a href="#The-Undercover-Economist" class="headerlink" title="The Undercover Economist"></a>The Undercover Economist</h2><p>This book was my first book I read that is related with Economics. So I found it hard to read at first, and I think that is because I read it in Chinese, the Chinese translation was a bit weird. The other books were read in English.<br>My biggest feeling toward <em>The Undercover Economist</em> was like: Uh-huh, and? It’s like talking about the hidden economics theories behind our lives, like the money you pay for coffee, how did they come from, sorts of. However, I think they were still too basic for me… I mean, everyone knows that your coffee comes from plants called coco, that is land, and there is labour, who will bring your coco to shops, and shops are capital, and people wrap your coffee, that is labour again, and who control the whole production line, enterprise. So what’s the point?</p><h2 id="Game-Theory-Analysis-of-Conflict"><a href="#Game-Theory-Analysis-of-Conflict" class="headerlink" title="Game Theory:Analysis of Conflict"></a>Game Theory:Analysis of Conflict</h2><p>I’m still reading this book but I think I’m almost done because the latter parts were like Statistics involving many weird symbols that I haven’t learnt.<br>The book also reminded me of HPMOR, and the whole game theory thing sounds really interesting, like they imagine both players are intelligent and rational, just like there were two main characters intelligent and rational in HPMOR. It also mentioned Bayesian theorem, which was actually what the author of HPMOR emphasized on in his book often. So when I read this book, I literally like was reading another HPMOR and it felt really comfortable. </p><p>I think I will just stop here and start talking about another experiment I want to do which is really fascinating you guys won’t believe that. I’m still reading economics books, and if I have any other thoughts I will update it in another blog.<br>That’s all thank you.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">So for the last few weeks, I&#39;ve been reading Economics books. Some of them really inspired me a lot.</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Life" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/categories/Life/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Economics" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Economics/"/>
    
    <category term="Review" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Review/"/>
    
    <category term="Reading" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Reading/"/>
    
    <category term="Reading List" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Reading-List/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>What is something you disagree with people about? Why do you think they are wrong and you are right?</title>
    <link href="https://olivezq.github.io/2023/02/14/why-not-relationship/"/>
    <id>https://olivezq.github.io/2023/02/14/why-not-relationship/</id>
    <published>2023-02-14T13:47:54.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-02-14T13:52:32.952Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It has been increasingly evident that the most overrated thing in culture today is the importance of love. It is therefore apt to consider whether people have been paying too much attention on their love romances than their career. People seem to hold the opinion that they can achieve more satisfaction from being in a relationship than jobs. Therefore, for the purpose of this essay, ‘in a relationship’ will be defined as a normal relationship between two partners who are loving each other and they are publicly announced as lovers, and ‘working’ will be defined as an activity involving mental or physical effort done in order to achieve one’s dream.</p><p>Individuals often consider their relationships bring them more happiness than their career, in other words, working can not give them as much satisfaction as being in love. According to Melanie Greenberg[1], being in a relationship can help partners become happier, healthier. In the meanwhile, the latest research report from the World Health Organization (WHO) [2] shows that within one year, 745000 people worldwide died due to long hours of work (death from overwork). When people talk about work, they are expected to show to be tired and depressed frequently, because working seems to be tied to “stress” and “overload”. According to a global public opinion survey conducted by Gallup Consulting in 2017, which the study combined 30 separate studies and data from more than 1 million respondents, 85% of the world’s 1 billion full staff authors are unhappy at work, and in Japan, this figure reached 94%. However, many people are still hoping to fall in love with others and have felt being happy in relationships, and this number is increasing. In a study from 2019 [3], 83% of American couples said they were happy in their relationship, while the percentage was only 63% in 2018. However, the accuracy of this view is still controversial.</p><p>The happiness gained at work is more direct. Good work results often bring direct material benefits, such as bonuses and dividends. These gains make people feel more secure and happy, because having money means they can buy almost anything they want. However, the happiness brought by love is psychological, which requires people to exert their subjective initiative to experience and comprehend. Materials can be turned into happiness anytime and anywhere, and the happiness brought by love needs certain conditions. For example, one can buy an Hermes with 10 million yuan at anytime at anyplace, however the happiness brought by love needs conditions: love each other sincerely, stick to each other, and no major catastrophic events. Individuals at work can get what they want through purchase, exchange and other behaviors, in a direct way.</p><p>Happiness in love is easily affected by external factors, for instance, the trivia of life, the mortgage of houses and vehicles and the physical conditions of each other. These factors may have a strong impact on love, which leads to people not being able to get happiness from love, but receiving endless anxiety. People can be worried about their partners’ health or increasing housing prices, which can lead to unhappy situations in a relationship and people can have fluctuating moods. On the other hand, the happiness gained in work depends more on personal efforts and is less affected externally. The harder individuals work, the more they earn, the happier they will be and the more sense of achievement they will have. The efforts in love may make they lose everything, since whether their lovers are satisfied with them are not under control and can not be tell.</p><p>Most people believe individuals can gain more satisfaction from love than their career. This essay contributes to the opposite statement by refereeing some relevant researches and evaluating the logic behind. It can be argued that jobs can bring more happiness than being in a relationship, as the enjoyment from working is more direct and is more stable to achieve.</p><p>References:<br>[1]Greenberg, M. (n.d.). Do relationships make us healthier and happier? Psychology Today. Retrieved January 13, 2023, from <a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/the-mindful-self-express/201612/do-relationships-make-us-healthier-and-happier#:~:text=Many%20research%20studies%20have%20shown%20that%20satisfying%20relationships,your%20health.%20Does%20relationship%20quality%20make%20a%20difference%3F">https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/the-mindful-self-express/201612/do-relationships-make-us-healthier-and-happier#:~:text=Many%20research%20studies%20have%20shown%20that%20satisfying%20relationships,your%20health.%20Does%20relationship%20quality%20make%20a%20difference%3F</a><br>[2]Pega F;Náfrádi B;Momen NC;Ujita Y;Streicher KN;Prüss-Üstün AM; ;Descatha A;Driscoll T;Fischer FM;Godderis L;Kiiver HM;Li J;Magnusson Hanson LL;Rugulies R;Sørensen K;Woodruff TJ; (n.d.). Global, regional, and national burdens of ischemic heart disease and stroke attributable to exposure to long working hours for 194 countries, 2000-2016: A systematic analysis from the WHO/ILO joint estimates of the work-related burden of disease and injury. Environment international. Retrieved January 13, 2023, from <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/34011457/">https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/34011457/</a> <br>[3]JericAs, N., Edgson, J., &amp; Drah, H. (2022, January 28). 21 Love Statistics &amp; Facts to make your heart skip a beat. 2Date4Love. Retrieved January 13, 2023, from <a href="https://2date4love.com/love-statistics/">https://2date4love.com/love-statistics/</a> </p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">It&#39;s a pile of rubbish kind of essay just don&#39;t mind about it.</summary>
    
    
    
    
    <category term="Psychology" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Psychology/"/>
    
    <category term="Writing" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Writing/"/>
    
    <category term="Essay" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Essay/"/>
    
    <category term="Mental" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Mental/"/>
    
    <category term="Relationships" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Relationships/"/>
    
    <category term="Career" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Career/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>To what extent is the UK government to blame for the current cost of living crisis?</title>
    <link href="https://olivezq.github.io/2023/02/02/towhatextent/"/>
    <id>https://olivezq.github.io/2023/02/02/towhatextent/</id>
    <published>2023-02-02T11:03:16.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-02-02T11:08:35.849Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It has been increasingly evident that the UK government played an important role in the current cost of living crisis. It is therefore apt to consider to what extent is it to blame for this crisis. Therefore, for the purpose of this essay, the phenomenons of cost of living crisis will be illustrated, and the behaviors of UK governments will be discussed.</p><p>The cost of living crisis of the UK nowadays can be concluded from varies features shown by statistics of the UK, for example, increasing inflation rate. In this essay, the crisis will be mainly defined as three significant phenomenons among these features, which are rising UK price levels, lack of food, and decreasing real salary. For the rising UK price level, according to the Office for National Statistics[1], inflation increased to 5.4% in Dec 2022, which was the highest of the last three decades. The biggest rises of price levels could be seen from transportation, food and furniture, which were all necessities in people’s life, and as these prices increasing faster than pay, there occured higher costs of living. Moreover, there was the biggest jump in food prices in Nov 2022 since 2005[2], more people could not afford to eat, which resulted in food poverty. UK residents also received the worst real salary decrease since 2000[3], and it was perdicted that European average for real-terms salary may be reduced further in the future, which meant the money workers earned are decreasing. As most individuals pay more and gain less currently, the UK faces the cost of living crisis.</p><p>In order to tackle the cost of living crisis, the UK government published a few policies to benefit the public. For example, the UK government announced in May 2022, that they were providing £37 billion of support in 2022, with all domestic electricity users receiving at least £400 to help with their bills[4]. Many families gained advantages from these assurances, however, there were still no major increases in benefits because the changes UK government made were mostly small that were not enough for people to avoid the living crisis as price levels were getting higher at faster speeds, while income tax may rises in real terms in the future[5], causing the crisis more severe. However, there were also increases in health and social care levy and minimum wage by the UK government, which could defuse the tense situation, although the extent of this easing up is unclear and seemed not solving the problem.</p><p>The decision of leaving the EU which was voted and made by the UK government in 2020 was also one of the causes of the cost of living crisis in the UK. Brexit meant that the UK no longer needed to pay membership fees, and the UK government had the ability to regulate trade costs by itself, along with other advantages, brexit could potentially save British households £933 per year[6]. However, the EU was the UK’s biggest trade partner, by losing its EU trading market, it made Foreign Direct Investments potentially decrease as the UK market itself seemed less attractive,which may causes the UK economy to slow down. But before brexit, the US also promised to provide its market to the UK according to Donald Trump who was the US president at that time, and with 300 million people in the United States, the consumption capacity was much stronger than that in Europe. However, when signing the free trade agreement between the US and the UK, Trump proposed several regulations that needed Britain to unilaterally open the agricultural product market, reform the medical insurance system and so on, which were not accepted by the UK government, resulting in the negotiation stalled and possibly not achieving the agreement in the future. By losing both US market and EU market, the UK government faced more severe economic problems since it had lower aggregate demand and less consumers, and unsmooth capital flow causes price levels to rise, causing cost of living crisis.</p><p>The war between Russia and Ukraine also affected the UK, and the UK government’s decisions towards this made UK residents’ life more difficult in some ways. As the US tended to help Ukraine, the UK government decided to support Ukraine too not only on the moral side but also because it wanted to stand on the US side and wait for it to sign a fair free trade agreement. When the agreement is signed, the UK could be able to have a bigger market and relax its tight economy. However, this also caused British enterprises to lose the Russian market, since the UK government refused to help Russia during the war, leading to a bad relationship between the two countries. The UK government also lost Russia’s cheap resources provision, for example oil and gas, which pushed up the price of energy and food in the UK, causing cost of living crisis.</p><p>In conclusion, the UK government should be blamed for the current cost of living crisis to a high extent. However, it is worth mentioning that the crisis could also be resulted from other influences such as COVID-19 and the UK’s ever-changing prime ministers. But such a crisis is still largely caused by the UK government itself, because it plays a greater role in this crisis, even if it does contribute to solving the crisis.</p><p>References</p><p>[1]Riley, C. (2022, January 19). UK inflation surges to highest level in 30 years | CNN business. CNN. Retrieved February 2, 2023, from <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2022/01/19/economy/uk-inflation-prices/index.html">https://www.cnn.com/2022/01/19/economy/uk-inflation-prices/index.html</a> <br>[2]McRae, I. (2023, January 23). Food poverty in the UK: The causes, figures and solutions. The Big Issue. Retrieved February 2, 2023, from <a href="https://www.bigissue.com/news/social-justice/food-poverty-in-the-uk-the-causes-figures-and-solutions/">https://www.bigissue.com/news/social-justice/food-poverty-in-the-uk-the-causes-figures-and-solutions/</a> <br>[3]<a href="https://hrnews.co.uk/uk-workers-received-the-worst-real-salary-decrease-on-record/#:~:text=Despite%20a%203.5%20percent%20nominal%20pay%20increase%20this,latest%20Salary%20Trends%20Report%20by%20ECA%20International%20%28ECA%29">https://hrnews.co.uk/uk-workers-received-the-worst-real-salary-decrease-on-record/#:~:text=Despite%20a%203.5%20percent%20nominal%20pay%20increase%20this,latest%20Salary%20Trends%20Report%20by%20ECA%20International%20%28ECA%29</a>.<br>[4]<a href="https://www.instituteforgovernment.org.uk/explainer/cost-living-crisis#:~:text=The%20%E2%80%98cost%20of%20living%20crisis%E2%80%99%20refers%20to%20the,has%20been%20further%20exacerbated%20by%20recent%20tax%20increases">https://www.instituteforgovernment.org.uk/explainer/cost-living-crisis#:~:text=The%20‘cost%20of%20living%20crisis’%20refers%20to%20the,has%20been%20further%20exacerbated%20by%20recent%20tax%20increases</a>.<br>[5]<a href="https://www.zdnet.com/finance/uk-cost-of-living-crisis-whats-happening-why-and-what-might-help/">https://www.zdnet.com/finance/uk-cost-of-living-crisis-whats-happening-why-and-what-might-help/</a><br>[6]<a href="https://www.shoutoutuk.org/2016/06/23/pros-and-cons-of-the-uk-leaving-the-eu/">https://www.shoutoutuk.org/2016/06/23/pros-and-cons-of-the-uk-leaving-the-eu/</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">887 words.</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Rationality" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/categories/Rationality/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Writing" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Writing/"/>
    
    <category term="Economics" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Economics/"/>
    
    <category term="Essay" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Essay/"/>
    
    <category term="COVID-19" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/COVID-19/"/>
    
    <category term="UK" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/UK/"/>
    
    <category term="News" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/News/"/>
    
    <category term="Politics" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Politics/"/>
    
    <category term="Brexit" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Brexit/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Analysis of My Life After Testing Positive</title>
    <link href="https://olivezq.github.io/2023/01/07/analysisofmylife/"/>
    <id>https://olivezq.github.io/2023/01/07/analysisofmylife/</id>
    <published>2023-01-07T08:41:50.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-07T10:03:21.156Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It was a normal afternoon.<br>I was sitting there as usual, and there was Mr.Keala speaking in pure Hawaii’s American accent as usual, and my lamp was open as usual.<br>“Ah, time for listening.”<br>I was thinking about this when I suddenly felt tired and my back started to fall and made me lye on my desk.<br>I forgot what happened after, but then I lied on my bed for the whole night, the next morning, I was 38.5 degree and my mum assured me that I was at least 40 degree last midnight.<br>So, how did all this happen?<br>Let’s rewind our time to last week.<br>I had a very long time wishing to have online lessons, I mean, everyone does that. So, when that day finally arrived, when I thought it was impossible but it still arrived, you can’t believe how happy I was.<br>On that day, Mr.Jacky walked in, stood besides the door, and said the most beautiful sentence I’ve ever heard: “After this class, everyone packs their schoolbags and leaves school, be real quick. From now on, we’re having online lessons.” That day was fortunately a sunny day, and the sunlight was in the classroom right away, I could even feel the green leaves outside calling for us. Everyone cheered except our Economics teacher.<br>So I went back home because of COVID-19.<br>And then after one week I got tested positive because of COVID-19.<br>I wasn’t very nervous, honestly.<br>But I wanted to figure out how did I got positive. So I asked Steven, who is my desk-mate, whether he had a fever. Because in my point of view, Steven is a rather outgoing person and he walked up and down stairs all day and met a lot of people, so if I got sick, probably he got sick too.<br>However, he didn’t. And he said maybe it was just a small fever of mine, which went totally wrong afterwards. But I appreciated him for comforting me.<br>Almost none of my classmates got a fever or something like COVID. I was like, “Okay I am the unlucky person, fine”. Olivia and Lucy were worried about whether they would get a positive too, because they were next to me during school, however they ended up to being tested positive three weeks later which was very long.<br>After our school closed down, every other school started to close down too. The benefits of this phenomenon was that, all my old friends started to be online again, like Lawrence and July, and even though we were in different schools we could still chat with each other. It felt like I went back to secondary school, but not totally. I heard many rumors from my friends, I guess that was a good effect too.<br>The drawbacks were, I felt like I was going to die when catching that virus, and I almost lost all the lessons. Although I could sit in front of the computer and I could catch up with the teachers even if I was sick, it still felt terrible, things blurred in my eyes, I couldn’t stop coughing and blowing my nose.<br>The most severe days were luckily on weekends, so I lied on my bed for two days just sleeping. Those days I was sleeping with no dreams, which was very rare after I recovered.<br>It took about two weeks for me to fully recover.<br>Things were more like a nightmare than those when I was not recovered.<br>I couldn’t possibly think, stand up, and speak. Not physically, but mentally.<br>I started to make more mistakes, even spelling mistakes in my essays, and whenever I hold up my pen, I couldn’t keep thinking for over one minute. Every time when I tell myself, I should be studying now, and I should finish my homework, my hands and brain started to refuse my commands. I found games and videos more interesting than they were before, and I read more novels than before. Sometimes I could read a novel non-stop for the whole morning, but I could not finish planning an essay for over ten minutes.<br>I’m not sure whether COVID had made my IQ got lower, but it definitely hadn’t made it higher.<br>As an INTJ, I was worried, anxious, and wanted to kill myself for days. On the other hand, I was still repeating the same daily routine, without plans without spirits. My mum was worried about my status on my study, like I wasn’t worried too.<br>I wanted to have full energy to welcome my every new day, but I couldn’t possibly force myself to get up, stand up. My brain was like having a block inside, I couldn’t pull it out, and it was stuck. Despite that, my memory had declined too. I started to have many dreams, and forgot them all the next day, only remembering those were not very desirable. Those dreams were tied together, like I was living in another universe, and I had to finish up the other world’s business before I came back to sort out the mess in this world.<br>I could hear Slytherin murmuring besides my ears every night. “You didn’t finish up the things you left for today from yesterday again.”He said, “Pathetic.” Anytime before I entered my mind palace, I fell asleep again.<br>Those were classic influences to a human of COVID-19.<br>And I haven’t find any methods to fully pull myself up from it.<br>So, I decided to search the Internet for methods that can help me to become energetic again. I’m going to list down the methods that I think can be useful and those that I’m interested in, so maybe they can help you too if you’re also experiencing this “not functioning” status.</p><h1 id="1"><a href="#1" class="headerlink" title="1"></a>1</h1><p>Write down the high and low points of your mood every day, and keep a journal. In this way, you will be more accepting of your own emotions and more comfortable without feeling trapped.<br>I’ve heard of this method from my high school Psychology teacher, who said we can keep a mood journal, which we can write down our happy feelings so when we look back we can become positive.</p><h1 id="2"><a href="#2" class="headerlink" title="2"></a>2</h1><blockquote><p>What is recommended in the book is a mode called interval training. The biggest advantage of this kind of training is that it only takes half an hour every day and can be completed at home. Taking running as an example, under normal circumstances, we will choose to run continuously for a certain period of time, while intermittent training refers to stopping for a rest after running for a minute or two until the heart rate returns to normal. The advantage of intermittent training mode is that it can improve the maximum oxygen uptake of the human body. The higher the maximum oxygen uptake, the higher the aerobic capacity of the human body, and the healthier the cardiovascular system. Because of the periodic mode of intermittence, the heart can also circulate between normal load and high-intensity load during exercise, enhance its toughness, and switch quickly between the two states. Just like a rubber band with excellent toughness, it can tie hair or bind RMB and shrink freely. To borrow a word from a friend who works in the sports rehabilitation industry, intermittent training can make people point where they are. It takes five minutes for others to recover. You may only take one minute.<br>The famous interval training is HIIT. I chose a HIIT training plan with moderate intensity from Keep to follow, three times a week. So far, it has been two weeks. However, I didn’t take a rest completely according to the time in Keep plan. Instead, I stopped exercising when my heart rate exceeded 160, and started again when my heart rate dropped to 100. I kept doing this until the training was completed. Therefore, my training time was always longer than the planned time each time, because I took longer to rest and recover. As shown in the figure below, my heart rate changed roughly periodically during the exercise.<br>Author: 老杨啃苞谷<br>Link: <a href="https://zhuanlan.zhihu.com/p/370895418">https://zhuanlan.zhihu.com/p/370895418</a><br>Source: Zhihu<br>The copyright belongs to the author. For commercial reproduction, please contact the author for authorization, and for non-commercial reproduction, please indicate the source.</p></blockquote><p>I’ve also read many other people’s opinions, and they’ve also mentioned keeping fit is a good way and keep exercising can help you have more energy.</p><h1 id="3"><a href="#3" class="headerlink" title="3"></a>3</h1><blockquote><p>People are animals driven by desire. How to make people build ships, you just need to make people yearn for the sea. If you are hungry, you will have an appetite. If you like a person, you will have a desire to dress up and meet him. If you don’t want to learn or paint, you can only show that you have no desire. Then set goals and rewards for yourself. For example, if you have learned all the learning content today/completed the amount of painting today, you will be rewarded with snacks, listening to songs, playing games, and traveling, eating, playing games, and buying new clothes if you get high scores in end-term exams.<br>Author: 乔米亚<br>Link: <a href="https://www.zhihu.com/question/557109598/answer/2704283421">https://www.zhihu.com/question/557109598/answer/2704283421</a><br>Source: Zhihu<br>The copyright belongs to the author. For commercial reproduction, please contact the author for authorization, and for non-commercial reproduction, please indicate the source.</p></blockquote><p>So, this one is like setting a goal for yourself to make you chase for it.</p><h1 id="4"><a href="#4" class="headerlink" title="4"></a>4</h1><p>Get up early and go to bed early.</p><h1 id="5"><a href="#5" class="headerlink" title="5"></a>5</h1><p>Do things you like. While for me, the things I like are writing novels, watching videos, playing games and sorts, however I don’t think they help to make me become more productive.</p><h1 id="6"><a href="#6" class="headerlink" title="6"></a>6</h1><p>Write down plans of your future. It terrifies me when people let me make plans for my future. It seems that my future is unclear. There are so many competitions, and jobs are hard to find.</p><h1 id="7"><a href="#7" class="headerlink" title="7"></a>7</h1><p>Watch things that can blame you until you wake up. This is a method that Claire told me. It helps to make you refresh, and make you fully understand that you need to get up.</p><p>All in all, the things above are my analysis.<br>I think I will plan them out… or not.<br>I think the things that I am interested in all have none-future-possibilities. Like Education, Philosophy, Linguistics, Sociology… these majors are all on the list of “the worst majors that you should never choose”, but I’m interested in all of them. Which was pathetic. Just by thinking about this make me feel sad, and there is no hope.</p><p>In conclusion, bye bye.</p><p>1780 words</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">It was a normal afternoon.</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Rationality" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/categories/Rationality/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Practical" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Practical/"/>
    
    <category term="Writing" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Writing/"/>
    
    <category term="Experience" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Experience/"/>
    
    <category term="Summary" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Summary/"/>
    
    <category term="Characters" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Characters/"/>
    
    <category term="Productivity" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Productivity/"/>
    
    <category term="COVID-19" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/COVID-19/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>「Christmas Special Collection」A Scavenger Universe</title>
    <link href="https://olivezq.github.io/2022/12/29/Christmas%20Special%20Collection/"/>
    <id>https://olivezq.github.io/2022/12/29/Christmas%20Special%20Collection/</id>
    <published>2022-12-29T10:45:37.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-29T10:49:00.631Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Since It’s Christmas already, I want to share with you guys some new writings I did on this special day. It’s a tradition of mine, since 2020. When it’s Christmas, I will write about random characters that maybe exist in another universe but definitely exist in my head, and what are they doing if they are having Christmas celebration just like us. By doing this, I can feel like I’m having my Christmas Day with them, so, it’s sort of like a way I paralyze myself to feel belong. Writing is my favorite hobby, and spending time with my <em>family</em> is also enjoyable.</p><p>Absolutely, I did the writing first in Chinese. But I will try my best to translate them into English.</p><p>I did many writings, but I think this one is the best.</p><hr><p>After receiving the message, Dubonnet put on a black windbreaker, finished the red wine in her glass, and went out of the house with her backpack on her back.</p><p>Even Christmas has cold nights. The family downstairs were watching the Christmas special of a cartoon, and the happy voices of the hero and heroine on TV passed through the thin air to the windows, without warming the cold street. The dim street lamps, the withered trees, and the female singer in Dubonnet’s earphones were hissing the lyrics of love.</p><p>The woman with short hair in ebony color got into the private car, as if a beetle was sneaking in the dark.</p><p>Japan also celebrates foreign festivals. Every family had decorated their houses. It could be seen from the windows that some families had also bought Christmas trees. The festival atmosphere in Mihuacho was especially more intense, and the night life could be as lively as day.</p><p>She drove to the Mihua Hotel without any expression. The children were taking group photos with Santa Claus in the hall. A tall electronic Christmas tree was set up in the middle. No one seemed to realize that a murder had occurred in a room upstairs.</p><p>As she walked into the elevator, “Jingle Bells” was still playing on the small TV, accompanied by the host’s background voice: “What is it? It was the sound of bells under the Christmas tree.”</p><p>Seeing Gin in such a living place, Dubonnet suddenly felt that “this is my kind”.</p><p>The man in black with a sense of oppression gave her a list of room numbers, threw the cigarette butt into the sealed bag in the hands of Vodka, leaving the smell of smoke and walked away.</p><p>Just passing by. Tonight, Gin seemed to have broken his record, killing at least five people in one night.</p><p>She knocked on the door of the first row of room numbers, and the first thing she saw was a very beautiful man, with a pair of eyes like phoenix’s looking at her.</p><p>“Merry Christmas!” he said, his voice muffled under his shield.</p><p>“Merry Christmas.” Dubonnet put down her backpack and put on her mask and gloves.</p><p>If Gin appeared, then 90% of the deaths were caused by gun shooting.</p><p>Being one of the scavengers working for “the Organization”, Sato Kui has her own code name, Dubonnet. This is not because she is a scavenger, but because she is not only a scavenger, but also a killer occasionally. Although the number of murders she did was very small, the Organization still gave her a code name because crime scenes had been cleaned up by her for ten years. After all, few periphery people can stay in the organization for such a long time. Sometimes it is a kind of self certification to survive.</p><p>For Dubonnet herself, ten years passed quickly. In the past ten years, she has had an idol and boss in the Organization, Gin, some long-term colleagues, and got into the Dongdu University. Her future life may also be like this. It’s so boring that she really thought it was better to die soon.</p><p>The short haired woman looked at the beautiful man who was staring at the body. He is HuaJiang Qin, one of her long-term colleagues.</p><p>“The internal organs of this body may be complete, so you can take them home. However, you may be disappointed if you want to have a brain.” Dubonnet walked up and wiped the blood on the window, “I shall say, before eating, you’d better take it to the research institute to check for viruses.”</p><p>“I know, I’m familiar with it (for cannibalism). Damn Gin, shooted against the brain, so annoying.”</p><p>Hearing what Dubonnet said, HuaJiang Qin did not hesitate to cut open the belly of the female corpse, took out the internal organs and put them away. Then he dragged the corpse into a bag and zipped it up.</p><p>After cleaning up a crime scene, they went to another room.</p><p>There was already someone else in this room. A child’s face poked out, but he was doing something unspeakable.</p><p>Dubonnet had been calm since she was shocked a few years ago. This was true. Different from HuaJiang Qin, who was known as “Hannibal of Japan”, he had a special necrophilia and was also her second long-term colleague.</p><p>They have been working together for three years.</p><p>“Zhenzhi!” HuaJiang Qin rushed close to Jin Zhenzhi, touched his head and mercilessly pushed the body away.</p><p>Dubonnet went through the process as usual. After cleaning up, she took the two people to the next room.</p><p>Finally, five rooms were cleaned up. It was already twelve o’clock at midnight.</p><p>They drove her private car to a bridge. In the quiet night, HuaJiang Qin happily plopped the bodies into the water.</p><p>She sat on a bag without a body, took off the mask and put it into the bag. On one side, the cold white color of Jin Zhenzhi seemed to glow under the dim street lamp.</p><p>Walking out of the bridge, there were fireworks blooming in the purplish red sky.</p><p>It lit up the deserted suburban streets and the eyes of the three fugitives.</p><p>Christmas, last year seemed to be the same.</p><p>“Hey… let’s go and eat Wudong Noodles.” HuaJiang Qin’s voice came.</p><p>“Cool.” She heard Jin Zhenzhi say.</p><p>“Yes! The Mihua scavengers start off!”</p><p>It was better not to shout such words.</p><p>The three of them ate Wudong Noodles which were a little slippery. HuaJiang Qin’s satisfied expression made Dubonnet felt as if she had just eaten human flesh.</p><p>“Here, Ping’an Fruit.” He took out three apples from nowhere, one for each.</p><p>This year’s Christmas seemed to be the same as that of ordinary people’s. At the thought of the scene where the body was just thrown, Dubonnet withdrew the idea.</p><p>However, when driving home, feeling the apple in arms, her mood was slightly different.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">When it&#39;s Christmas, I will write about random characters that maybe exist in another universe but definitely exist in my head, and what are they doing if they are having Christmas celebration just like us.</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Rationality" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/categories/Rationality/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Writing" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Writing/"/>
    
    <category term="Characters" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Characters/"/>
    
    <category term="Sweet Imagination" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Sweet-Imagination/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Ideas On &quot;Showbiz&quot; Genre Novels</title>
    <link href="https://olivezq.github.io/2022/12/11/showbiz/"/>
    <id>https://olivezq.github.io/2022/12/11/showbiz/</id>
    <published>2022-12-11T07:37:17.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-11T08:15:30.735Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<hr><h2 id="This-is-an-another-article-that-I-wrote-without-planning-and-it-contains-just-some-thoughts-that-simply-flow-from-here-to-there"><a href="#This-is-an-another-article-that-I-wrote-without-planning-and-it-contains-just-some-thoughts-that-simply-flow-from-here-to-there" class="headerlink" title="This is an another article that I wrote without planning and it contains just some thoughts that simply flow from here to there."></a>This is an another article that I wrote without planning and it contains just some thoughts that simply flow from here to there.</h2><p>Some days ago I was reading some “showbiz” genre online novels because I had read a few online fictions in the past, and I found showbiz genre quite interesting.<br>First I will define what showbiz genre is. Showbiz genre is the kind of genre where the stories take place in showbiz, where the hero and heroine are usually pop-stars or they are willing to become pop-stars, and this kind of genre usually contain stories like “becoming the most famous star on the world” or “romance between two famous stars” or “from the most hateful star to the international top-star”.</p><p>What I want to illustrate is, I want to analyze the market of this kind of genre’s online fictions, and provide some examples based on my readings and evidences, and finally suggest a way that can help to make writers’ showbiz genre novels become better-selling if they want to write showbiz genre… I think I will also compare the differences between showbiz and other genres and point out the advantages of showbiz over the others so writers can enlarge them.<br>Again, I might not have all the data because I’m only doing this for fun and economics, and you just don’t have to treat my suggestions seriously but I will be very grateful if you really do think my advice is helpful.</p><h1 id="The-Market-of-Showbiz-Genre-Online-Fictions"><a href="#The-Market-of-Showbiz-Genre-Online-Fictions" class="headerlink" title="The Market of Showbiz Genre Online Fictions"></a>The Market of Showbiz Genre Online Fictions</h1><p>So this is a specific genre, and I’ve specify my range into “online fictions”, so I think nobody has ever done this analysis(maybe?).<br>I checked Bing academic search engine and found nothing, then I checked Bing search engine, and found that there are 50 kinds general genres of books that most people agree about, however showbiz is not included in that webpage. Also there is no analysis of market of online fictions (even), at least I didn’t find any.<br>Do I need to draw a Demand Supply Diagram? (Probably don’t have to…)(just kidding)<br>It’s my second time doing a market analysis and my first time doing the whole market analysis on my own so… don’t expect it to be so expertise.</p><p><a href="https://postimg.cc/Hj7Cpx8M"><img src="https://i.postimg.cc/T2t2J5Rt/Wechat-IMG1689.jpg" alt="Wechat-IMG1689.jpg"></a></p><h2 id="1-1-Macro-environment-Analysis-PEST"><a href="#1-1-Macro-environment-Analysis-PEST" class="headerlink" title="1.1 Macro-environment Analysis (PEST)"></a>1.1 Macro-environment Analysis (PEST)</h2><p>Can’t believe I’m treating this seriously…Emm…<br>As shown in the diagram above, I used the PEST method to analysis the macro-environment and I will discuss it more specifically in words.<br>So, <strong>Politics</strong>! I’ve checked a VERY scientific website, and I found this.</p><blockquote><p>On June 1, 2021, the newly revised Copyright Law of the People’s Republic of China will come into force, further improving the system of punitive damages for infringement, as well as the definition and type of works. The legitimate rights and interests of creators will be more effectively protected in the future. The new Copyright Law adapts to the development of new Internet technologies and the new era background of market economy, and ensures the basic order and basic legal rules for the development of the network literature industry.<br>– <a href="https://www.huaon.com/channel/trend/834844.html">The Development Status of China’s Internet Literature (Online Literature) in 2022</a></p></blockquote><p>So it seems like there are new policies for online fictions writers to protect their rights and for readers who support legal online reading websites. Let’s hooray, advocates!<br>For online fictions themselves, they have low liability on governments and policies. The same reasoning as when you run a WeChat official account.<br>However, online fictions can not involve things that relate with the real world or, you’d better not involve them. Because this can cause troubles for your books, like some organizations might not like your description about them and then report you up, who knows? One example is the famous  <em>I’m Such A SuperStar</em> event. This event I will talk about it later. What’s interesting is that this book is just the genre “Showbiz” we’re discussing. So showbiz genre fictions should especially pay attention to try not to include real life things and events.</p><p>For <strong>Economics</strong>, I think it is clear that online fictions including those showbiz genre are in a perfectly competitive market. There are many substitutes at low costs for books, and there are many substitutes for genres too, like any reader can switch from showbiz genre to fantasy. On the other hand, online fictions are non-rival, which means there can be illegal spread of the fictions and readers can read them without paying money. However, there is an increase in investment in online fictions these years, as online fictions have a huge inclusion of new technologies. The consumption is also increasing, as technology improves, 5 billion people in China read online fictions. But I didn’t look up for data like “consumer consumption total amount”.</p><p>For <strong>Social</strong>, online fictions have a bright future. 50% of China population are teenagers and adults, and they are the main users who read online fictions, another big user ‘the elderly’ also takes up a huge proportion of population, about 25%. Nowadays people demand for relax and break from tiring work and they seek for a sense of accomplishment to gain satisfaction, and online fictions can undoubtedly satisfy them in this mental health. However, in China, the consumer consumption index (CCI) is decreasing, from 120 in Feb 2022 to 86.8 in Dec 2022.</p><p>On the <strong>Technological</strong> side, the writers can provide new kinds of showbiz books to readers. As technology improves, there can be varied forms of showbiz genre books, like comic, audio, e-book, video, acting, and even VR. Some books can even develop IP, and sell derivation. Platforms that provide online fictions are also increasing, and advertisements nowadays are also increasing(which can help to influence people reading fictions online, thanks to <em>Tomato Novels</em>).</p><p>These pictures are analysis based on the whole online fictions’ market on <a href="https://www.huaon.com/channel/trend/834844.html">The Development Status of China’s Internet Literature (Online Literature) in 2022</a>.<br><a href="https://postimg.cc/V0XTXJXH"><img src="https://i.postimg.cc/kGHm38G9/Wechat-IMG1682.jpg" alt="Wechat-IMG1682.jpg"></a></p><h2 id="1-2-Target-users-of-the-study"><a href="#1-2-Target-users-of-the-study" class="headerlink" title="1.2 Target users of the study"></a>1.2 Target users of the study</h2><p>I just took photos from the website.<br><a href="https://postimg.cc/1g4jJCpF"><img src="https://i.postimg.cc/d09cQg35/Wechat-IMG1684.jpg" alt="Wechat-IMG1684.jpg"></a><br><a href="https://postimg.cc/3dtM1DPP"><img src="https://i.postimg.cc/P5jttWKr/Wechat-IMG1685.jpg" alt="Wechat-IMG1685.jpg"></a></p><h2 id="1-3-Industry-analysis"><a href="#1-3-Industry-analysis" class="headerlink" title="1.3 Industry analysis"></a>1.3 Industry analysis</h2><p>I’ll skip this part because I don’t have an industry.<br><a href="https://postimg.cc/9R5s0P7q"><img src="https://i.postimg.cc/xCcQstjg/Wechat-IMG1686.jpg" alt="Wechat-IMG1686.jpg"></a><br><a href="https://postimg.cc/xqPBjzTc"><img src="https://i.postimg.cc/ZKkmc8GF/Wechat-IMG1687.jpg" alt="Wechat-IMG1687.jpg"></a></p><h2 id="1-4-Porter’s-Five-Forces"><a href="#1-4-Porter’s-Five-Forces" class="headerlink" title="1.4 Porter’s Five Forces"></a>1.4 Porter’s Five Forces</h2><p>Threat of new entry: I think there must be new entries of online fictions. Like new genres, who knows? Before <em>Ghost Blowing Lamp</em> came out, few people know about Tomb robbing genre.<br>Suppliers Power: Well we do have a lot of suppliers. In fact, anyone can become a supplier. Being a writer takes no costs.<br>Buyers Power: We also do have a large range of buyers. See the structure of users graph above.<br>Threat of substitutes: Ahh… this one is large too…<br>Competitive Rivalry: We do have a lot of competitors. And there is quality differences.</p><h1 id="some-examples-based-on-my-readings-and-evidences"><a href="#some-examples-based-on-my-readings-and-evidences" class="headerlink" title="some examples based on my readings and evidences"></a>some examples based on my readings and evidences</h1><h2 id="2-1-My-own-examples"><a href="#2-1-My-own-examples" class="headerlink" title="2.1 My own examples"></a>2.1 My own examples</h2><p>I’ve seen many showbiz genre fictions, so to prove that writing online fictions is super easy, I’m going to show you how showbiz genre fictions have repeatability by writing some general stories in showbiz genre. As the saying goes, “I’ve never eaten pork, and I’ve seen pigs run”.</p><p><em>Bai JinGe woke up to find out that she had time travelled into a book, and into an evil supporting female character who is also called Bai JinGe. Angelic b!tch heroine? Scumbag hero? And there are a lot of fake news and rumors towards her online? See how she turn back the powers of darkness, get over mistress, kick off jerks, and become the goddess of showbiz! One cold and austere movie king:”Time to go home, baby.”</em><br>So, usually in this kind of fictions, the heroine will first have a lot of black history on her, and her parents hate her, and her fiancee hates her, and her sister wants her dead, then she will use her superpower to become more and more popular, and then catch a movie star’s attention, usually this movie star never falls in love and is cold to everyone, and usually this star is handsome than anyone and have a lot of money, and then he will fall in love with the heroine, they will face a lot of obstacles, and finally get married and get about 3 or 4 children while everyone is celebrating their love romance.</p><p><em>Luan Zhiqin time travelled into a book that she was the real daughter of a rich family but was trapped by the fake daughter. As she is no longer the fearful coward real daughter from the countryside, she dressed herself up and shocked everyone. “Sister, what are you doing?” The fake daughter. “Luan Zhiqin, you are our daughter!” The Luan parents. “Three minutes, I need that woman’s identity.” One unknown handsome rich CEO. She smiled, became the world-famous top-star.</em><br>Yeah so usually these stories are about a female time travelled into a book, and the writers mixed the powerful family genre with the showbiz genre. The hero is a wealthy and young CEO of a world-famous company, and the heroine is a talented and skillful actress and top-star.</p><p><em>How did I end up here? Lu Xing was still gasping when she entered a man’s room. Wait, I have a fiancee? Wait, shouldn’t my fiance be ugly and disabled? Why is this man here handsome and… looking at me with such yearn? One night, she had a husband that was the richest person on the world. And that man promised her:”I will never let anyone hurt you.”</em><br>So… this one is like, the hero and heroine get married first and then fall in love later. The heroine became top-star, and the hero is helping her all the way long, hooray! No logic!</p><p><em>Being killed by her beloved sister and her loyal fiance, she returns and lives another life, she promises she will beat up all the people who hurt her. Su Marie was filled with anger, and used all her energy to take her revenge. “Su Marie, get me C brand’s latest design!” “Su Marie is dead.” She replied with cold words, and became the top-star, journalists and film directors rush into her house. “Miss Su, is it true that you are chasing Mr Mo?” “No, it’s I’m chasing Miss Su.” A handsome man who she has never seen appeared in front of her house, passed over the mic.</em><br>The heroine had a second life, and revenged. When she’s revenging, she caught the hero’s attention, and the hero is usually a movie star or CEO, and he deeply fell in love with her and was interested, then they will get married and have 4 children!</p><p><em>She was the world top 1 assassin Eagle, the world top 1 hacker Q, the world top 1 composer Blue, the world top 1 fashion designer Iris, the world top 1 CEO Lao Bai… Now she lives another life, becomes an unknown student in a poor village. Yan ChunYu coldly regain her glory again, and becomes a world-famous C-pop team member. Later on, her identity was discovered by people, hacker, composer, fashion designer… A man:”She is my fiancee.”</em><br>Usually in these books, the heroine has many identities and probably is too rational and cold to others. Then she will be warmed by the hero, and get married! Classic online fictions.</p><h2 id="2-2-evidences"><a href="#2-2-evidences" class="headerlink" title="2.2 evidences"></a>2.2 evidences</h2><p>First the <em>I’m such a SuperStar</em> event. This book was one of the famous showbiz genre books, and was banned because of containing political issues and blaming the country’s social media and stuff like that… so…</p><p>I think the number one nook for showbiz genre is <em>Showbiz is Mine</em>. The heroine and hero both lived a second life. And what’s very inspiring and new is, in the first life, the hero was heroine’s light, and in the second life, the heroine was the hero’s light. So this whole thing is like, completely impossible to happen in real life because it requires the opportunity to live a second life, which is more interesting than those just simply revenge for their second life.<br>But the book still has some disadvantages. It’s the first only because the other ones are too bad.</p><p>The number two on my list is <em>Antitandem</em>. The heroine is a girl who deeply loves acting, and was talented in it but had no background, while the hero is a singer. What’s good about this book is that, the hero and heroine are not the relationship of “I’m helping you because I love you”, but “I don’t know why we meet up again but I think I like your light”. They meet each other in total accidents and had the kind of soul connections, but not simply, “woman you interested me”. The writer did this one good. The characters of the heroine were revolutionized. However, the hero was a bit blanked.</p><h1 id="some-suggestions"><a href="#some-suggestions" class="headerlink" title="some suggestions"></a>some suggestions</h1><p>You need to make your novel new and inspiring.<br>You need to make your novel outstanding.<br>If you write showbiz, you can not only write showbiz. You need to show the other side of the world. You need to have enough knowledge and eyesight, to see what’s really behind showbiz and what it’s really like. You can’t just go right up there, and make up fake stories that are not be possible to happen in real life. You can’t make up characters that are plane.<br>You don’t know what’s really happening in a showbiz. So you need to see it, then write it. You need to see others’ work of showbiz genre, you need to watch documentaries about showbiz, you need to read books about showbiz.<br>You need to know the background. That’s the basic skill of a writer.<br>You need to make your characters new. Your characters should be not just CEOs or assassins. Your characters should be solid and dynamic. They need to be felt like real person, but not just a name.<br>Your story should focus on showbiz. And outweigh what’s unique about showbiz.<br>I think I will write a showbiz genre fiction on my own to illustrate myself more clearly.<br>You see, there are actually a lot of stories to write in a showbiz, it’s such a splendid world with so many plots you’d never imagined. You can locate anyone your heroine or hero, they don’t have to be the famous pop star, they don’t have to be a CEO and a hacker at the same time, they can be a film director, an actress that only likes acting, a hostess, a journalist… They don’t have to be famous, they can shine in their own ways.<br>So, these are my suggestions. Keep your things new.</p><p>In conclusion, I did this article poorly… Because I think I fell in sleep during writing… Anyway hope you like this update.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">If you write showbiz, you can not only write showbiz.</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Rationality" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/categories/Rationality/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Writing" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Writing/"/>
    
    <category term="Economics" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Economics/"/>
    
    <category term="Showbiz" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Showbiz/"/>
    
    <category term="Novels" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Novels/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>1128</title>
    <link href="https://olivezq.github.io/2022/11/28/112899/"/>
    <id>https://olivezq.github.io/2022/11/28/112899/</id>
    <published>2022-11-28T03:28:28.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-28T13:49:49.661Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>。。。。。爱。。。爱。。。。。。。。。爱。。。爱。<br>。。。爱。。。。。。。爱。。。。。爱。。。。。。。爱<br>。。爱。。。。。。。。。爱。。。爱。。。。。。。。。爱<br>。爱。。。。。。。。。。。。爱。。。。。。。。。。。。爱<br>。爱。。。 。。。。。。。11281128。。。。。。。。。。爱<br>。。爱。。。。。。、 。。11281128。。。。。。。。。爱<br>。。。爱。。。。。。。。。。.。。。。。。。。。。 爱<br>。。。。爱。。。。。。。。。.。。。。。。。。。 爱<br>。。。。。。爱。。。。。。。.。。。。。。。。爱<br>。。。。。。。。爱。。。。。.。。。。。。爱<br>。。。。。。。。。。爱。。。。。。。。爱<br>。。。。。。。。。。。。爱。。。。爱<br>。。。。。。。。。。。。。。 爱</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Just want to celebrate today. 1128</summary>
    
    
    
    
    <category term="Nothing" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Nothing/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Being Awake</title>
    <link href="https://olivezq.github.io/2022/11/27/beingawake/"/>
    <id>https://olivezq.github.io/2022/11/27/beingawake/</id>
    <published>2022-11-27T05:17:49.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-03-10T12:29:23.358Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>How is your work efficiency when you stay up late? Do you feel ashamed when you want to sleep while others are studying?<br>You see, a few days ago my teacher asked my classmates when did they go to bed. Almost everyone of them said, “11:30”, or, “12”. Somebody said “5 a.m”. And a month ago, one of the Student Union President candidates pointed out in his powerpoint, that one of his strengths, is “Stay Up Late”. I remembered that clearly because I was the hostess, and I myself also stayed up late for writing scripts. My peers ask and compete about their sleeping hours, the fewer the harder you work.<br>Everyone is trying to be awake.<br>So my point here is, this, “being awake” is the most overrated thing in culture today.<br>It seems that when you are awake, you have more time than others. And when you wake up at 10 am while others wake up at 6, you lose 4 hours behind. Maybe somebody reviewed Chemistry ahead of time already, and you still haven’t done your homework. You don’t know what others are doing, you don’t know how far they’ve gone. You only know that the thing you can do is keep chasing. And sleeping cannot help you catch up with them.<br>So the reason why we overrate “being awake” is this anxiety, this feeling of we need to make our time lucrative.<br>But does being awake really make your scores get higher? Or it just let your brain stops working because it never rests?<br>Do you think it is meaningful to do this worthless consumption of time, to have this rat race?<br>What “being awake is overrated” is really implying is, we are having irrational internal competitions or “voluntary” competitions.<br>Once everyone was sleeping quietly, suddenly a classmate got up and began to study and made some achievements that were maybe actually not strongly related to staying up late, you would find that the whole class’s atmosphere was gradually distorted.<br>Another example is when some students did past-papers of the past 5 years, it will result in others doing 10 years, or even 20 years, while that doesn’t make your grade gets higher because the syllabus changes from time to time, and some old past-papers are not valuable.<br>We should never overrate the value of “involution”, the cause of being awake.<br>What is meaningful on the other hand, is being flexible. We can tighten, we can loose. When we are flexible, we will not regard winning as the only value of the game.<br>Sleep when it’s time to have a rest. Because in today’s culture, “being awake” is the most overrated thing. Stop having involution.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">So my point here is, this, &quot;being awake&quot; is the most overrated thing in culture today.</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Rationality" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/categories/Rationality/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Practical" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Practical/"/>
    
    <category term="Writing" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Writing/"/>
    
    <category term="Life Improvements" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Life-Improvements/"/>
    
    <category term="Speech" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Speech/"/>
    
    <category term="TEDx" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/TEDx/"/>
    
    <category term="Involution" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Involution/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>How to Jump Out of Your Comfort Zone</title>
    <link href="https://olivezq.github.io/2022/11/06/comfort-zone/"/>
    <id>https://olivezq.github.io/2022/11/06/comfort-zone/</id>
    <published>2022-11-06T03:26:08.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-06T03:39:18.491Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Since secondary school, I’ve been reading popular articles written by famous successful adults about “you should jump out of your comfort zone”. It’s not that I <em>want</em> to read these, I mean, I’d rather memorize more Chemistry notes than spending time on these most-of-the-time-not-very-helpful stories. But I still get recommendations on these stuff on social media. And they were like, “Hey, do you want to succeed in thirty seconds?”, and I would be like, “Sure!”, and then they would say, probably most of them, “You should manage your time and force yourself to be self-esteem!”, and I would be like, “Okay but I don’t know how so I’ll go read my online fictions.”. And that’s basically the whole thing. They don’t tell you how, and they make the whole process of becoming successful looking easy. And “Jumping out of your comfort zone” is just one of the small tips they will give you.</p><p>However, when I was still young, I spent a lot of time on figuring out how on earth can I “jump out of comfort zone”. So you see, They say we people have our own comfort zones and it is easy for us to just sink in there, and relax and die. And I thought that was terrible. It’s like those fairytales in which a frog jumped into a pot of warm water, and somebody turned the fire on, and the frog just slowly died with the temperature slowly rising. But I never figured that thing out. I went to school, I ate, I drank, so where was my comfort zone? You can’t find it, because it’s invisible to you, and if you can find it, then why you call it comfort zone when comfort zone is just designed to let you sink and die without notice?</p><p>It’s ironic, that I finally understand the whole comfort zone concept when I started playing video games.</p><p>I was playing a game, where you need to give out your cards to beat others. You can have many cards, but you can only choose to bring about eight cards at a time. You can also choose a character for your cards, who can give you buffs. You can earn game coins to upgrade your cards and characters. And that’s basically the background.</p><p>At first, I used a character, which I used for a very long time, let’s just call her Beta. Beta can summon demons for you. And I found that was easy, powerful and can beat the other player to death quickly. I later tried a few other characters, won a few games, and return to Beta. I won almost every game, using the same cards and the same character. But things changed when I get to a higher level. People were stronger than me so much, and I got stuck in my level. I could not get higher.</p><p>That’s when I realized I need to make a change. I changed some of my cards, but still using Beta, because I only know how to use Beta. However, I still couldn’t win, and even became more terrible at it.</p><p>I started to look at my records. Actually, that was the first time I noticed there was a function called record in my game. So I copied others’ cards and characters, and tried to beat players by using others’ methods.</p><p>Then I began to win again, by using Lucifer. Lucifer is a character who will summon animals for you. It takes a long time for Beta to summon demons, but for Lucifer she can summon animals when you want her to. However, the longer time you wait, the stronger animals you summon.</p><p>And that, was the first time I jumped out of my comfort zone. And let’s call this jump ‘Level 1 Jump’. Because I only changed my character, changed my methods, but I still hadn’t jumped out entirely.</p><p>I started losing again. So I started using other cards, because in the past I was only paying attention to a few of my cards that I always use. However, I still lose. The reason I found was that I was still using my old cards while trying new cards. And if I kept using these old cards, I would not have the opportunities to use new cards because I was used to using old ones and would prefer them when I had to choose between old and new. As a result, I changed <em>all</em> of my cards into new ones, tried a few that others had been using but I myself never used before, and a few I had never seen people using it before.</p><p>In the first few games I lose because I wasn’t used to using them. However, once I got used to them, I started to win every game, just like before, and I was still learning other new cards. Some cards I found useless when using Beta seemed to be strong when using Lucifer, and some cards which I couldn’t understand the meaning of it before seemed to be helpful when using Smoker. </p><p>And that, was the second time I jumped out. ‘Level 2 Jump’. But, there could still be improvements.</p><p>As I’ve just illustrated before, we need coins to upgrade cards and characters in order to make us strong. So there is actually a lot of other things we can do in the game besides beating other players. </p><p>I’d never tried to figure out what the red ones can do when I can just use blue ones. That’s an old  issue of mine, which my Math teacher in my secondary school once told me. “Number 11,” she said, “You are used to using those old methods. You would rather use 1+1 than 1x2 when you first learnt multiplication. But sometimes questions can only be solved by multiplication. So try to use new methods, to solve in more efficient ways.” She asked me how long I spent on my homework. I said 2 hours a page. She was looking at me like, “See, I told you!”.</p><p>So I started to try figuring out what the red ones can do. I started trying new functions in that game, I took part in teams when I was used to fighting on my own, I figured out how to collect coins and what does a shop can do, I found the red ones can bring me more than blue ones. It was like using multiplication rather than adding. Another thing I learnt from this, is that whenever we study we should first know what it is, then do our exercises. You can’t just look at a function, and say, “Okay I guess I’m not good at this because it is red. “ and then you walk away to play the other functions. At least you should try a new function for three times, then decide whether you like the outcomes, and whether you’re good at this.</p><p>And finally, this is the third time I jumped out of my comfort zone, and I can still jump for more, but for now, we just call this ‘Level 3 Jump’.</p><p>In reality, things are not quantitative like those in games. You can’t know how people see you, while on the other hand you can read likability from NPCs. And you don’t have cards, you don’t have characters to play.</p><p>However we can still jump out of our comfort zone. As I’ve just say, we can try new things, use new methods. We can try to take part in clubs after-school, or go running before going home, or take a shower before doing our homework. We can try riding bikes to school, sleep like Da Vinci, drink one more glass of water everyday. </p><p>It’s like developing temporary habits, and then choose those habits you like to make them permanent. Keep curious, keep innovate, keep trying new, and that’s how we jump out of comfort zone. You need to jump out of your mind set, and seek new ways to live.</p><p>There’s no conclusion just do it.</p><p>A/N: This is nonsense I wrote. No academic writing, no grammar just read it for fun. I was just trying to write some stuff following my mind without making scripts and record my experience of playing game. Thanks for reading.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">There&#39;s no conclusion just do it.</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Rationality" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/categories/Rationality/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Practical" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Practical/"/>
    
    <category term="Writing" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Writing/"/>
    
    <category term="Experience" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Experience/"/>
    
    <category term="Life Improvements" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Life-Improvements/"/>
    
    <category term="Productivity" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Productivity/"/>
    
    <category term="Comfort Zone" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Comfort-Zone/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Notes on &quot;How We Should See the World&quot;</title>
    <link href="https://olivezq.github.io/2022/10/22/notes-on/"/>
    <id>https://olivezq.github.io/2022/10/22/notes-on/</id>
    <published>2022-10-22T07:51:31.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-22T08:01:27.951Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few weeks ago, I read an article about two young writers who write online fictions and recently were interviewed by some journalists.</p><p>They were two girls living together, and both of them publish their fictions on a website called “JinJiang”. I do not recall the whole specific story, but just the basic. One of the girls tried to kill herself, because her readers did not like her new book, and even though they write a lot everyday, they can only get little money since they are not famous writers on that website. They suffer and struggle everyday. In the end, the girl was saved and she was considered attempted suicide.</p><p>If you search on the website, you can see that: If the length of a single chapter of a work on JinJiang is 5300 words, the sales amount of this chapter each time is 0.018X5300/1000=0.0954 yuan, which is 0.095 yuan after rounding. If 2000 people buy this chapter, the total income of this chapter is 0.095X2000=190 yuan. If there are 50 vip chapters in the signed work, and the number of characters and sales volume are kept above, the total income of the signed work is 190X50=9500 yuan.</p><p>This seems a lot, but can you really write 5300 words per chapter <em>and</em> have at least 2000 readers <em>and</em> write 50 vip chapters in a limited time? Not to mention, whether your writing can become vip chapters? What’s more, your money can only <em>actually</em> get to your account when your  <em>whole</em> book is finished.</p><p>Some people said that those two girls were lying. However, there is always this undeniable fact: Writers of online fictions earn little money.</p><p>To be more general, who are these writers? Most of them are people who are passionate about creating fictions, or people who do not have a high educational background so that they do not have any skills that can provide them with better jobs. </p><p>Well… let’s just dip it more deeper so I can illustrate fully my points.</p><p>One kind of these writers, as I’ve just said, are people who really <em>love</em> writing.</p><p><strong>But</strong>(you see here is a <em>but</em>), these individuals are usually not highly educated or do not know how should they have a better life. Going back to where we started, we said these <em>full-time</em>(so now I am talking about full-time, but not part-time, so I am not suggesting all writers) workers publish <em>very long</em> writings on <em>JinJiang(or any other websites where you read online fictions)</em>, and I am not talking about those very famous writers like <em>priest</em>(though even them could earn more money than they got from JinJiang if they choose <em>LR</em> method but not <em>SR</em> method(and again these two methods I will illustrate afterwards)). So, they like writing. Then, since there are so many paths to choose when you want to chase your writing dream, why did they choose this one?</p><p>Information failure is one reason. Most of individuals especially teenagers have seen so many online fictions and <em>reading</em> them seem to be fun(however they do not consider what the situation will be like if they start <em>writing</em> them), so they may think, publishing fictions on websites would be easy and enjoyable and can make money. And what they do not know is, they can not make much money by doing this job, and typing words all day long would be stressing and it will not be much better than writing their 2000 words essays (and even <em>essays</em> require less words than fictions). On the other hand, maybe many of the writers prefer to have their own websites or they want to publish their books in bookstores, but they do not know how. Or, in another expression, they <em>do not know how should they have a better life</em>.</p><p>Another reason is that they have limited eyesight. Why they have limited eyesight? The most significant reason is they have received poor education(which many people would have agreed). They do not see that, despite the SR method, there is a LR method. *By SR and LR method, I am suggesting methods in the short run and methods in the long run(which are similar to those SRAS and LRAS in Economics). </p><p>SR method is this: You want to publish your fictions. The most obvious way you can think of is to publish them on JinJiang. And this way has no entry, no requirements, no threshold(you can see this as the perfectly competitive market), it is the easiest way. Also, because you have been hearing stories from your elders about famous writers always have to overcome an obstacle of earning little money to achieve their dreams, and many editorial offices require you to have received high education, you decided to just publish works on JinJiang. (So you see here, the benefits of writing on JinJiang and the disadvantages of selling books in bookstores have been enlarged due to people’s propaganda, and maybe they even do not mean it, for example, textbooks tell stories about a popular writer who can only eat bread and drink water everyday when he was not famous, but students only see how hard writing to editorial offices can be; While on the other hand, websites keep advertising, and too many successful stories of online authors are being told.)</p><p>LR method is this: You want to publish your fictions. Although you know that you could just use JinJiang, you also know that you can just create a whole new website of your own, or publish your workings by selling books. And, you also know, most of the money you made for your books will go to the websites themselves but you can only get few percentage. So, in the long run, it is better to take control of your whole money instead of giving your money away to your company. Some reason happens on when you are looking for a new job. Although you can just work for a company, you can actually create your own business even though it is harder, but the outcome can be more than you could imagine. </p><p>In this case, I will talk about people who received high education but choose the SR method. They are those kinds of people who have limited eyesight and they do not see the LR method. You could say, they could have chosen LR. </p><p>And for people who received low education. They choose this path, because they have no choice.</p><p>So, how to avoid suffering like them but live a better life?</p><p>We should <strong>see the world in a different way</strong>.</p><p>So finally we come back to our topic: How we should see the world.</p><p>A few days ago, I was chatting with Olivia about the 22nd Meeting (which is the 22nd National Congress of the Communist Party of China), and we happened to talk about the future. Which is also why I had the inspiration of writing this blog.</p><p>I said, “See what’s the fact but not listen to opinions.” </p><p>This is basically the first step of seeing the world differently.</p><p>Facts come from the origin, the true cost, the real result of an event, and they are not a statement. For example(a very classical example), there is a glass of water, and it is half-filled. Pessimists would say “there is <em>only</em> little water left”. Optimists would say “<em>great!</em> so now we <em>still</em> have some water”. People are being suggested to behave like optimists, because they often have higher happiness(but there is this drawback: they may be unable to deal with bad situations in time due to blind optimism). While some other people are used to being pessimism, because when the result is not as bad as they thought they can feel better, and they can be prepared for all the very worst results. However, what rationalists see, is just a “glass of water half-filled”. They will not consider whether it is good or bad. It is just a glass, with some water, and if that is the whole fact then that is it. When they hear a new, they attempt to look for the facts in the new. If a famous rockstar was reported for being racism, they would got back to where the event started, and see what did the rockstar really do, instead of listening to others’ ideas like “I heard he did a racism thing” and believe in them.</p><p>Sometimes facts can be only found by doing experiments. For instance, you do not know whether your Physics teacher is a good or bad teacher. And you have just met each other, so there is no specific fact. If you want to know the answer as soon as possible because you need to decide whether to hire a tutor outside school, you can try to do experiments. First, you make an assumption. “Our new Physics teacher has limited skills.” seems like a good start. So now you specify your question from “good or bad” to “skillful or lack of experience”. Then you design your experiment. Outline what you need to prepare, like “finding a very hard Physics question and see how well he explains the question”. You do the experiment. And then you make your conclusion from the observation you made! If you like, you can even do the experiment three times. This seems easy, and everyone has done that without even realizing they are doing experiments like scientists, but in reality most people actually just instantly look for others’ comments (you do not even realize you are doing this because this seems normal). So think about this method before you make <em>any conclusions</em>.</p><p>Or sometimes you can not do experiments. Then you can only try to seek for more evidences to support your idea, which is why logic is important. However, it is not right to <em>only</em> seek for facts that are beneficial to you. You can not just state “the moon is made of cheese” on the bottom of the page, and then go back to list a bunch of reasons why you think the moon is made of cheese. If you do that, then that is just Politics. You should always stay suspicious, because your previous conclusions could be wrong, and maybe there is more possibilities, maybe you got a new fact that “ghosts do exist”, so now you need to consider the probability of “my Physics teacher sometimes may be occupied by another person who is not good at Physics which is why he teaches badly”. Which is also why we should often try to <em>jump out of the mindset</em>. <strong>And</strong> which is also why we should not be afraid of making mistakes, and be brave to admit that we fail.</p><p>The second step is to realize that your starting point, education background and vision determine your livelihood, your happiness and your life.</p><p>There once was a TV show, where they asked a group of students in the same school to stand on  the same starting line on a playground. Then they asked questions like “do your parents have stable jobs” or “have you been travelled around the world”, and if your answer was yes, then you could go 5 steps further to the next starting line. In the end, some students stood far away from the finishing line while some students had already gone across half of the playground. <em>Then</em> the hosts asked them to run for the finishing line in order to win a prize.</p><p>The TV show just made your starting point visible. Although everyone looks like having the same life and having the same opportunities competing on the same stage, their starting points actually are formed in the very beginning. However, you can always fight as hard as you can to chase the others, because this is just the starting point. All roads lead to Roman.</p><p>Why we study? If I did not study, I would not have thought so much about this. We study because we want to have better jobs, have better life, meet better person, and to know the world better. Knowledge is not only about “Physical Quantities” or “Chemical Bonding”, but also about “how to express yourself more clearly” and “how to become more rational”. Not to mention, your education background decides what companies you can go to because that is just how the world goes on.</p><p>Your vision enables you to see where you can possibly go. People who keep gossip everyday and hating someone who accidentally poured their water, are trapped in a small cage where they lock themselves, and that they can only see these trifles. You should not just look at the present, but also pay attention to the future. And you should never stop thinking. Those people who succeed are always those who seek the opportunities.</p><p>Standing on your starting point, improving your educational background, and watching as far as you can.</p><p>Forget all about the people you hate, the entertainments that are not beneficial for your future, the blame that you irrationally put on things you just do not like, and just do what you should do, improve what you should improve.</p><p>And that is my suggestion.</p><hr><p>2200 words, 12262 characters</p><p>– the one who will tear down the universe</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Your starting point, education background and vision determine your livelihood, your happiness and your life.</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Rationality" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/categories/Rationality/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Practical" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Practical/"/>
    
    <category term="Writing" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Writing/"/>
    
    <category term="Economics" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Economics/"/>
    
    <category term="Life Improvements" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Life-Improvements/"/>
    
    <category term="Philosophy" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Philosophy/"/>
    
    <category term="How to See the World" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/How-to-See-the-World/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>How Do I Spend My Everyday Life</title>
    <link href="https://olivezq.github.io/2022/10/14/Daily-Rountine/"/>
    <id>https://olivezq.github.io/2022/10/14/Daily-Rountine/</id>
    <published>2022-10-14T13:44:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-14T13:51:06.542Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Things to say in the beginning:<br>In this webpage I will illustrate my daily routine, because it is time for me to update my GitHub and I just thought: “<em>Okay, why don’t I just do this.</em>“ So I do this. There is no specific reason, just something I came up with.</p><h1 id="6-00-A-M"><a href="#6-00-A-M" class="headerlink" title="6:00 A.M."></a>6:00 A.M.</h1><p>I usually wake up at 5:55 a.m., however most of the time I just lie in my bed and wait until it is 6 a.m., then my alarm on my phone will ring with symphonic kind of vibration. With another 10 minutes, I still lie on my bed, and then finally I dress up.</p><p>In 20 minutes, I finish my breakfast and wear sunscreen just to avoid suntan. Then I check the bus mini-program on Wechat to see whether my bus has coming.</p><p>Often I get on the bus at around 6:50 a.m..</p><h1 id="7-00-A-M"><a href="#7-00-A-M" class="headerlink" title="7:00 A.M."></a>7:00 A.M.</h1><p>On the bus, I read my e-book just to fully use my spare time, currently I am still reading <em>Harry Potter and the Methods of Rationality</em>, for the third time.</p><p>When I arrive at school it is often early, at almost 7:15 a.m.. At this time, I will plan and outline my whole day using a planner book, putting what classes I will have and what to do today on it, and sketching out timelines. When I finish writing, it is usually time for class, and for those times when I finish planning ahead of time, I do past-papers exercises.</p><p>After each class, I will note down on my planner about what did we learn in three lines. This helps me focus on lessons and review, and also remind me of what to review when I go home. Sometimes, when the teacher announce that a test is coming, I will write down the day and what the topic is of the exam with blue pen on the planner beside my review, just to highlight.</p><p>During breaks, I go to the toilet or chat with my friends, or I go upstairs to hand in Math homework because at school I am one of the Math representers.</p><h1 id="12-00-A-M"><a href="#12-00-A-M" class="headerlink" title="12:00 A.M."></a>12:00 A.M.</h1><p>I go to the school canteen to have my lunch at about 11:55 a.m.. After that, I will hang out with my friends and do past-papers exercises. Or if I have any questions, I will go upstairs to ask my teachers, because we have a long break after lunch.</p><h1 id="5-00-P-M"><a href="#5-00-P-M" class="headerlink" title="5:00 P.M."></a>5:00 P.M.</h1><p>We finish our day at school at 5 p.m.. Then my friends and I will go running. Usually we just run for 3 rounds around the playground, about 900 m, and then go home by 5:20 p.m..</p><h1 id="7-00-P-M"><a href="#7-00-P-M" class="headerlink" title="7:00 P.M."></a>7:00 P.M.</h1><p>Going home with my e-book reading, it is usually 6:00 p.m. when I arrive home. Then I send the homework into our class’s QQ group since I am the study monitor, and I plan my evening on my planner.</p><p>First I review again what I did today, then I figure out what things that I haven’t done yet and I will list them as my evening tasks. Next, I will look at my habit tackler, and check whether I have followed daily goals like <em>“drinking 8 glasses of water”</em> or <em>“eat less sugar”</em>, and then do tasks like <em>“learning Korean/Spanish”</em> and <em>“Pipa Practice”</em>. After finishing up most of the things on my tackler, I will do the evening tasks.</p><p>Then I will receive a call from a friend of mine in another school, and we will chat for a while just to share how our life is going.</p><p>I have an alarm on my phone that it will ring at 9:00 p.m., which will remind me it is time to go to bed.</p><h1 id="9-00-P-M"><a href="#9-00-P-M" class="headerlink" title="9:00 P.M."></a>9:00 P.M.</h1><p>I speed up to finish my day work when it is 9 p.m.. I usually manage to finish all of them at 9:30, depending on whether I need to wash my hair that day because washing hair means longer time spent on showering. </p><h1 id="10-00-P-M"><a href="#10-00-P-M" class="headerlink" title="10:00 P.M."></a>10:00 P.M.</h1><p>Most of the time I can go to bed at around 10:00 p.m. I do this because I need to make sure that I have 8 hours sleep everyday, from 10 p.m. to the other day’s 6 a.m.. When I am really busy though, I go to bed at 10:30 p.m..</p><p>However, on weekends I can sleep whenever I want.</p><p>And this is basically my day.</p><p>It is still not very productive, but I enjoy this kind of life. Especially when I run with my friends after-school, looking at the sunset, thinking nothing but just focus on running, it is always a pleasure.</p><p>However, sometimes when I cannot function, unwilling to do anything, I just think in my own world without following my schedule.</p><p>End.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">This is about my daily rountine. Basically just about how I spend my day.</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Life" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/categories/Life/"/>
    
    <category term="Rationality" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/categories/Life/Rationality/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Practical" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Practical/"/>
    
    <category term="Experience" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Experience/"/>
    
    <category term="Study Tips" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Study-Tips/"/>
    
    <category term="Life Improvements" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Life-Improvements/"/>
    
    <category term="Productivity" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Productivity/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Virus</title>
    <link href="https://olivezq.github.io/2022/10/06/virus/"/>
    <id>https://olivezq.github.io/2022/10/06/virus/</id>
    <published>2022-10-06T07:11:56.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-06T07:17:30.826Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>He walked. Like he always did. And he had no idea of when will this whole thing ends. As a doctor the only thing he was doing now was working all day long. He thought nothing could make him feel pain anymore. He had seen enough bodies, lying and wanting to get a little more oxygen and he and his team could not do anything. He walked past another body which was lying on the floor. The whole hospital thing was just like a nightmare, especially when everyone should be at home with families, enjoying the spring festival. And he had no right to blame the god.</p><p>The afternoon of this day, when they finally can rest for a 10-minute, his college said: ”what is it to feel like?…like, everything has become dark, and the only hope is to live.” He made no response. His college goes on: ”And, you breathe, so heavily that your lungs burn, but still no oxygen comes into your mouth, and finally, everything went still, left nothing……” His college went fast asleep on the desk. Another college came in, looking quite calm and he said, there is another patient that needed to be rescue. He stood up, although knowing that there was only a little possibility that the patient could live and there had only been 3 minutes since he sat down.</p><p>He went into the room. There was a man standing, having a call on his phone. He recognized the man was the patient’s son. The man was breathing heavily, and every word he said came out by a heavy sound. The patient on the bed was still though, but the heart beats of the old man had become more and more slow. It only took six heart beats for him to know that, the old man was dead. When he past the son of the dead old man, he knew that, the son would never be there again, the son won’t be anywhere soon, but with his father.</p><p>When he closed the door, he thought of his son. The music his son loved to listen to, the smile his son gave before he left home a month ago, and finally, his son himself.</p><p>In the evening, one of his colleges was crying in the staff room. Her daughter had just died because of the virus. He wanted to face this fact like he usual did, but then an image of his son had just pop out in his brain. HIS SON, just be a space occupied by his absence, just a hole without a voice, or a face, or fucking anything signature to his son. Her daughter was gone. Permanently. Always. And maybe one day, his son would be just like her daughter, and it would all because of the virus. He wanted to shake off this thought, but it was so stubborn that it didn’t will to disappear. A drop of tear slowly came down to his chin.</p><p>He missed his son.</p><p>A/N: This is a fiction I wrote when the COVID-19 first broke out in 2021 winter. So, I wrote this when I was in grade 8 in secondary school. Anyway, thanks, for listening.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">An English fiction I wrote when I was in grade 8.</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Life" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/categories/Life/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Health" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Health/"/>
    
    <category term="Writing" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Writing/"/>
    
    <category term="2021" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/2021/"/>
    
    <category term="Fiction" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Fiction/"/>
    
    <category term="ESL" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/ESL/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Book Review:Bad Blood:Secrets and Lies in a Silicon Valley Startup</title>
    <link href="https://olivezq.github.io/2022/10/06/badblood/"/>
    <id>https://olivezq.github.io/2022/10/06/badblood/</id>
    <published>2022-10-06T06:48:47.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-06T07:44:38.150Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This book is called Bad Blood. And it was written by a journalist, which means all the stories in the book are based on actual facts. It is a book which I read during the summer vocation. And here are some reviews that I personally think are important.</p><p><img src="https://tse3-mm.cn.bing.net/th/id/OIP-C.p6X4T3aV1HFRrRqlHRBs0gHaLO?w=179&h=271&c=7&r=0&o=5&dpr=2&pid=1.7" alt="BadBlood"></p><h2 id="First-the-advantages"><a href="#First-the-advantages" class="headerlink" title="First the advantages:"></a>First the advantages:</h2><ul><li>The author is very powerful in creating a repressive and high-pressure atmosphere within the company. He not only said that “people in this company are terrified”, but also made people realize the inhumanity of Holmes through various facts. For example, he mentioned that Sandy, the second senior manager of the company, set up all the cubicles as glass rooms. Sandy laid on the glass every day to find out what employees were lazy, so that he could dismiss them. For another example, it is mentioned in the book that there were a group of people in the company called “Brotherhood”. They were all friends of Elizabeth’s brother, and their only entertainment activity in the company every day was to calculate how long they sneak out to play today without being found by Sandy.</li><li>The whole company is perfectly highlighted by the author as cold, inhuman, repressive, formalistic and other characteristics. Whenever an employee couldn’t bear to resign, Elizabeth would not even tell any employee about the resignation of that person. When an employee died unexpectedly, the whole company was no different and continued to work, like a ruthless machine. Many motivational quotations were hung in the office building, and even many quotations were painted on the wall, which was always in contrast to the coldness of the company.</li><li>The author described the whole story in very strict words. From entrepreneurship to bankruptcy. In the early stage, he described a lively and ambitious girl, and in the later stage, he wrote a stubborn and angry CEO of the company. The transition was natural, as if he was looking at a person’s life rather than just a story.</li><li>The author has a strong and fluent writing skill. He described Elizabeth, Sandy and others vividly through language description of appearance, etc. For example, when the author described Elizabeth’s cover in Fortune: “She wore a black turtleneck sweater, black mascara set off sharp blue eyes, bright red mouth, and beside the eye-catching title: ‘CEO living for blood’. “The black turtleneck sweater was an appearance feature that the author had always emphasized, as was her deep voice. This is what the author wants to highlight. Elizabeth’s leadership image is actually an imitation of Apple’s Jobs (trying to be the second Jobs) It is also a metaphor that Elizabeth’s shiny appearance is actually a lie, because as mentioned earlier, Elizabeth had an extraordinary obsession with Jobs and often wore black turtleneck sweaters similar to Jobs after accepting friends’ suggestions.</li><li>It truly reflects: bragging about your products, obtaining funds, and covering up your real progress, hoping that the reality will eventually catch up with your boast. This phenomenon is still tolerated in the technology industry.</li><li>At the end, he pointed out that at the beginning, when Elizabeth dropped out of Stanford University 15 years ago, she did not want to cheat investors and trap patients in a dangerous place. Everyone believed that she sincerely believed in a vision and devoted herself to it to realize it. But in the gold rush of the “unicorn” craze, and in the process of her all-out pursuit of becoming the second Steve Jobs, there was a turning point when she stopped listening to wise suggestions and began to seek shortcuts. Her ambition was too greedy to tolerate any interference. This paragraph is really a perfect summary of all the above.</li><li>It reminds us that we should not trap the white wolf with our bare hands. It also tells us that it is good to have a dream of benefiting mankind, but if we don’t pay attention to the product itself and exaggerate it, we will end up suffering from the consequences. The bubble of lies will eventually burst. Seeking shortcuts will not only fail to harvest success, but also lose self.</li><li>The structure of the story is tight and compact. None of the details is nonsense.</li></ul><p><img src="https://tse3-mm.cn.bing.net/th/id/OIP-C.1gDT2EQ3ZKFy7KvC1rSvjwHaOG?w=116&h=180&c=7&r=0&o=5&dpr=2&pid=1.7" alt="elizabeth"></p><h2 id="Disadvantages"><a href="#Disadvantages" class="headerlink" title="Disadvantages:"></a>Disadvantages:</h2><ul><li>The early story is too bland, and there are many summaries of previous stories, which may make some readers give up halfway.</li><li>The level of Chinese translation is relatively poor.</li><li>The author likes to repeat the name of the character instead of using him or her instead, but it is much better than Crime and Punishment.</li></ul><p><img src="https://ts1.cn.mm.bing.net/th/id/R-C.39571570dac5d7ecddad26188199c62c?rik=1r/vjniwYGdPng&pid=ImgRaw&r=0" alt="elizabeth2"></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">This book is called Bad Blood.</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Rationality" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/categories/Rationality/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Economics" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Economics/"/>
    
    <category term="ESL" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/ESL/"/>
    
    <category term="Review" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Review/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>AS EAQ Full Mark Essay Writing</title>
    <link href="https://olivezq.github.io/2022/09/20/Elon%20Musk/"/>
    <id>https://olivezq.github.io/2022/09/20/Elon%20Musk/</id>
    <published>2022-09-20T10:56:39.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-09-20T11:12:40.534Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Task:<br>Write an essay about a genius, 150 words.</p><p>Model Answer(28/30):</p><p>Elon Musk: An Undeniable Genius<br>It is difficult to say that Elon Musk, the CEO of Tesla, is just a common man. So much of his genius is obvious.<br>Elon Musk attended the University of Pretoria when he was only 17 years old. He then moved to Canada and went to Queen’s University and University of Pennsylvania, before he received bachelor’s degrees in economics and physics.<br>In 2004, Elon Musk joined Tesla Motors, and four years later became its CEO. Before that, he was also the founder of Space X and Paypal. His work life has been very successful, making him become the richest person on the world, with a wealth of $213.9 million in 2022.<br>On the other hand, his family life has not been so ideal. Elon Musk described his father “evil”, and his second wife described her relationship with Elon Musk as “fluid”. This world’s wealthiest person stated that he did not like his father at all who had too many children, when he himself has nine children.<br>In conclusion, Elon Musk is a lengendary person, who is undoubtly genius.</p><p><img src="https://n.sinaimg.cn/sinacn/w1920h1080/20180209/a188-fyrkuxs8703069.jpg" alt="ElonMusk"><br>About:<br>This is an essay about Elon Musk. The score was 28 indeed, but eventually it became 30 as a full mark because our teacher “used a curve when grading”.(I don’t know the theory but I think it’s good)</p><p>Addition:<br>Elon Musk is the origin of Iron Man.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">A full mark writing for AS EAQ about a genius.</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="IGCSE" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/categories/IGCSE/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Writing" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Writing/"/>
    
    <category term="ESL" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/ESL/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>高一学期总结（升学篇）Summary of the First Semester of High School (Activities)</title>
    <link href="https://olivezq.github.io/2022/08/31/%E9%AB%98%E4%B8%80%E6%80%BB%E7%BB%93%E5%8D%87%E5%AD%A6/"/>
    <id>https://olivezq.github.io/2022/08/31/%E9%AB%98%E4%B8%80%E6%80%BB%E7%BB%93%E5%8D%87%E5%AD%A6/</id>
    <published>2022-08-31T10:22:55.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-08-31T10:34:28.932Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="升学"><a href="#升学" class="headerlink" title="升学"></a>升学</h1><p>时间总占比：60%</p><h2 id="IOLC语言学奥林匹克竞赛"><a href="#IOLC语言学奥林匹克竞赛" class="headerlink" title="IOLC语言学奥林匹克竞赛"></a>IOLC语言学奥林匹克竞赛</h2><p>奖项：<br>新秀组区域站个人High Distinction Top 10%<br>新秀组中国站团队Distinction Top 15%</p><p>语言学，我最初是被人工智能语言学吸引到的。我一开始想报名哲学奥林匹克竞赛，后来看到了语言学奥林匹克竞赛，就被它的介绍惊讶了。它从名字上听起来，是一个小众的竞赛，但实际上它非常有含金量，是MIT推荐项目之一，知乎上还有人毫不避讳地说，进了IOLC专业组国家队就可以上麻省理工。<br>但是让我对语言学感兴趣的，还是因为它和人工智能有关。初中的时候发现了一个网站<a href="https://www.lesswrong.com/">Lesswrong</a>, 里面有许多关于人工智能的讨论。从此以后，我对科学和人工智能有了一定了解和兴趣。<br>后来，我对IOLC这种只需要解谜就可以拿分的竞赛感到着迷，并且决定为它开设一个社团。<br>在杭州，我参加国赛时，和我一个房间的女生非常友好，我们相处很愉快。团队里大家都是随机分配到的队友，所以之间并不是很熟悉。在团队赛中尴尬地沉默了几十分钟才开始互相讨论。<br><a href="https://postimg.cc/64nVRtvC"><img src="https://i.postimg.cc/Wzf5B4pY/Wechat-IMG1262.jpg" alt="Wechat-IMG1262.jpg"></a><br>总而言之，IOLC体验感还是很强的。<br>因为IOLC这项竞赛非常有趣，我也在学校开设了IOLC语言学与推理社。</p><h2 id="IEO经济学奥林匹克竞赛"><a href="#IEO经济学奥林匹克竞赛" class="headerlink" title="IEO经济学奥林匹克竞赛"></a>IEO经济学奥林匹克竞赛</h2><p>奖项：<br>新秀组区域站个人Distinction Top 20% 团队High Distinction Top 10%<br>新秀组中国站团队Distinction Top 30%</p><p>IEO的话，和NEC的体验感是差不多的。整个团队关系融洽，当时在酒店基本就是这个样子的：</p><blockquote><p>没有阳光，灰蒙蒙的天，错综复杂的交通线路，蚂蚁般的人类和小车移动。<br>“为下游的企业…“<br>一架平板立在桌上。男人平平的语调听得人想睡觉。<br>“他提出来的那个什么棒球的行业，说实话我不是很了解…“<br>”但是我们的行业要定下来…“<br>”我们给两个选择，让gloria选择一下…“<br>”它只要体现出你的深度和广度就可以了，我们…“<br>张笑阅躺在转椅上，此时那个视频解析已经关闭，房间里的众人正在激烈地讨论。<br>“哦好的…OK OK OK…我知道，我耳朵在听呢…“<br>张旖宸声音频频响起。<br>“什么新冠的核酸检测吗？”<br>“新冠的核酸检测和食品安全是一样的吗？…“<br>从张笑阅的电脑中传来一个中年女性的声音，和酒店里的四个青年人商讨着。<br>不时的笑声活跃了气氛，链接一个接一个，打字的声音四处撞击着墙壁。</p></blockquote><p>和IOLC的团队气氛完全不能比。<br>后来甚至张笑阅和王子萱即兴合唱了一首歌。<br>还是很强的。明明来自南京上海苏州三个省份，却像是见了故人一样。<br><a href="https://postimg.cc/dZjkw1CN"><img src="https://i.postimg.cc/prgDQ5Lv/Wechat-IMG1265.jpg" alt="Wechat-IMG1265.jpg"></a><br><a href="https://postimg.cc/TK4yRByx"><img src="https://i.postimg.cc/MGW1YSqn/Wechat-IMG1264.jpg" alt="Wechat-IMG1264.jpg"></a></p><h2 id="NEC全美经济学挑战赛"><a href="#NEC全美经济学挑战赛" class="headerlink" title="NEC全美经济学挑战赛"></a>NEC全美经济学挑战赛</h2><p>奖项：<br>DR组区域站区域个人国际经济与时事优胜奖<br>区域团队国际经济与时事优胜奖<br>区域团队微观经济学优胜奖</p><p>以下为我在金中剑桥公众号上的同学分享：<br>NEC作为全球经济学比赛，PRE、DR、AS三个赛级难度依次增大。高一刚开学，队长张笑阅提议我们参加DR级竞赛，一开始我很惊讶。我们从未学过经济学，仅有三个月的时间，如何与已有大量知识储备的高年级参赛者做同一套赛题呢？最终，其他同学都选择了PRE。而带着极大的勇气，我们决定尽最大努力。<br>我们（张笑阅、杨奇坤和我）加入了学校的经济社接受进一步辅导。我们同时学习微观和宏观、了解国际时事，因为备赛时间并不多。<br>三个月转瞬即逝，赛前紧张，赛时尽力，赛后焦急。一天下午，队长以紧急的语气给我发了短信，是“晋级”的消息。接下来的一个小时，我们的电脑都在忙着回复祝贺信息。<br>回想这个队伍刚组建时，没有人预料到这会为我们带来其他任何事件都无法比拟的独特实践知识和感受。我们成功超越了全国一半以上的DR参赛者。所有这些美好的果实，都是来自帮助我们的老师，支持我们的父母和同学，以及战队中的每一位。</p><h2 id="UKMT英国数学竞赛"><a href="#UKMT英国数学竞赛" class="headerlink" title="UKMT英国数学竞赛"></a>UKMT英国数学竞赛</h2><p>奖项：银奖</p><p>关于数学竞赛，我并没有获得很好的奖项，或者说，考到很好的成绩。我的数学成绩挺好，但是一到竞赛就考不出高分，可能是练得太少了。</p><h2 id="金陵中学国际部Spelling-Bee拼写大赛"><a href="#金陵中学国际部Spelling-Bee拼写大赛" class="headerlink" title="金陵中学国际部Spelling Bee拼写大赛"></a>金陵中学国际部Spelling Bee拼写大赛</h2><p>奖项：团队铜奖</p><p>在年级比赛的时候，抽的单词都是我们没有背过的。我还记得，最后我抽的那个单词是“hypocrite”，意思是“伪君子”。我之前听歌的时候听到过这个单词，因为我有一个朋友自称伪君子，所以印象比较深就记下了，比赛的时候就拼出来了（那首歌名是Psycho）。于是我角逐了年级第一。<br>后来和中美比赛的时候，抽的单词都在考前一个假期给了我们背的。我是投机取巧，找到当时规则里的漏洞，把各个单词的字母数都背下来了，这点和高二的一个学姐想法一样。最后学姐的反应速度更快，并且我自己也是囫囵吞枣背的，总是犹豫，最后的最后就是团队第三。</p><p>以下为我在金陵中学公众号上的同学分享：<br>Legendary, 这是我们的队名。<br>我是剑桥高一二班的郑旗，Spelling Bee A队的一名队员。随着本届金中国际部Spelling Bee拼词大赛落下帷幕，我们队取得了团队铜奖，另一支剑桥队获得了团队金奖的殊荣。<br>在为期两个月的准备过程中，我们获得了长足的进步与积累，不但学习到很多以前没学过的单词，也因为某些单词而了解到让人感兴趣的领域。<br>在为期一小时的激烈比赛中，每个队都遇到了各式各样的难词。我们队通过团队合作成功解决了这些难词中的大部分。虽然有些机会因为没有来得及抢到而错失，但由此我们仍然感受到团队合作的重要性，体味到齐心协力，才能创造更大的奇迹。在比赛中，我们也领略到了其他队队员的风采与敏捷，无论奖牌或是经历，相信大家都有丰富的收获。<br>再次翻阅为这场比赛准备的单词表，细细密密，从第一个单词aberration开始，共有超过350个的单词量。除了255个是必答部分，还有99个是抢答，加之今年新增的冬奥主题抢答部分，大略有500个单词了。既然是参加拼词大赛，那就得带上胜负心。毫不讳言，为了提高训练次数和为竞赛热身，我从将要比赛的那周开始请同学们反复抽查我的单词掌握情况。承蒙同学们的厚爱与不弃，那一周我每天都完成了热身训练。许多同学除了给予我热心的关怀和支持，还对我的表现作了精彩点评。每每听到这些或热情、或肯定、或勉励的话语，常使我感怀，令我愧疚，也给我更多向上攀登的动力。<br>在此祝愿金中国际部步履不停，无忧亦无惧。也祝愿剑桥班的每一位同行伙伴——愿你有满腔孤勇，眉间永远盛放光彩。剑桥Legendary，一起向未来。</p><h2 id="Speak-Out青少年演讲比赛"><a href="#Speak-Out青少年演讲比赛" class="headerlink" title="Speak Out青少年演讲比赛"></a>Speak Out青少年演讲比赛</h2><p>奖项：无</p><p>这个比赛，是最近才出现的，由ITCCC举办的，青少年演讲比赛。演讲这个东西说实话，很玄，ITCCC没有给出很标准的主题，只给了一些参考主题，让我们自己讲自己的。这导致你并不知道评委们喜欢什么样的主题，我当时是从参考主题里选了一个<a href="https://olivezq.github.io/2022/06/19/ArtAndMusicTherapy/">why art and music therapy should be covered by health insurance</a>，但是我那一场里最终奖里都是类似”how did I succeed””not ordinary but extraordinary”这样的主题。<br>组委会要求我们开头要介绍自己，但是评委在最后点评的时候说：你们讲得都很好，但是我有一个小建议就是，你们开头的时候可以不要自我介绍，直接讲就可以，那样可以更让听众身临其境。所以说，这场比赛，漏洞百出。<br>我从这场比赛里大多获得的还是经验。它让我知道了演讲稿不能写太多，但是要引人入胜，而且要和听众有联系。不能怯场。</p><h2 id="剑桥大学夏校"><a href="#剑桥大学夏校" class="headerlink" title="剑桥大学夏校"></a>剑桥大学夏校</h2><p>参与证书</p><p>剑桥大学的夏校让我看到了剑桥大学的高质量教课水平。我印象最深的是古典学课，因为说到古典学，我就想到贵族公子小姐在弹钢琴跳芭蕾的场景，但是我一开屏，古典学教授就是一副邋遢但精神抖擞的模样，可以说和优雅沾不上关系，甚至完全没有其他教授的偶像包袱，这种冲突感让我记忆犹新。<br>夏校还开放了论坛，在那里我们可以回答教授的课堂问题，和其他同学一起讨论，增加参与感。</p><h2 id="学生会"><a href="#学生会" class="headerlink" title="学生会"></a>学生会</h2><p>担任学生会通用部部员</p><p>除了运动会让我拍几张照外，学生会没给我过任何任务了。最后学生会优秀部员里也没有我。<br>可能是我不擅长交际，没有主动问任务他们也就没有给我。<br>这种感觉就像是在黑衣组织里，你终于成为了代号成员，结果因为你不活跃，导致负责你的琴酒忘了有你这个人，你也变得很闲，最后BOSS评选最佳员工的时候，在一众卧底和社畜里看到你的业绩为零，给你了个什么奖也没有奖。<br>导致体验感极差。</p><h2 id="英才计划"><a href="#英才计划" class="headerlink" title="英才计划"></a>英才计划</h2><p>这个计划是针对普高的，我没有选上是因为当时和生物的录取线差了几分。我为了选上甚至把普高的生物必修1和2两周内自学完了（因为其实我生物不是很好，虽然我写过一篇和蝴蝶有关的论文），但是其实到场考试范围真的很广，没选上也是在我意料之中的。<br>从这次计划中，我获得的是普高生物知识。这个经历也让我成为怂恿我同桌开生物社的罪魁祸首之一，想着在生物社学一学教一教就不枉我学了两周普高生物了。</p><h2 id="班委"><a href="#班委" class="headerlink" title="班委"></a>班委</h2><p>担任学习委员</p><p>在班级，我担任学习委员。有些和学习有关的事情其实轮不到我干，各科的课代表大部分都会主动负责自己学科的作业之类，班主任在学习相关的事务上也有时亲力亲为或者让班长代劳。<br>我主要是负责每天晚上到家在群里发作业，在班会课上参加和学习有关的分享。在每天发作业这件事上，我的参与感还是很强的，相当于每天打卡。<br>我还经常参与班级板报和宣传等。</p><p>暂时关于升学就写这么多，想起来其他的还会更新。</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">IOLC,IEO,NEC,Spelling Bee...and more</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Life" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/categories/Life/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Experience" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Experience/"/>
    
    <category term="Summary" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Summary/"/>
    
    <category term="NEC" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/NEC/"/>
    
    <category term="Study Tips" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Study-Tips/"/>
    
    <category term="Activities" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Activities/"/>
    
    <category term="IEO" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/IEO/"/>
    
    <category term="IOLC" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/IOLC/"/>
    
    <category term="Linguistics" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Linguistics/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>高一学期总结（标化篇&amp;学科篇）Summary of the First Semester of High School (IELTS &amp; IGCSE)</title>
    <link href="https://olivezq.github.io/2022/08/24/%E9%AB%98%E4%B8%80%E6%80%BB%E7%BB%93/"/>
    <id>https://olivezq.github.io/2022/08/24/%E9%AB%98%E4%B8%80%E6%80%BB%E7%BB%93/</id>
    <published>2022-08-24T13:18:15.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-02-25T06:29:28.615Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="标化"><a href="#标化" class="headerlink" title="标化"></a>标化</h1><p><strong>时间总占比：10%</strong><br>刚一开学摸底，ESL就获得了170分的A等的我在英语方面并没有花费很多力气。深知自大使人失败的道理，我并没有松懈，而是该上的雅思课还是上。<br>但是，因为对自己英语能力的自信，我并没有做多雅思练习。比起同样在备战雅思的同学们，尤其是那些上一对一、在假期每早签到自习刷题的认真同龄人们，我全年的练习加起来甚至不能超过他们一天的练习量。<br>怀揣要露陷的心情，我2月去参加一场模考，结果写作只有5分，口语只有6.5分。不过，听力拿了8分，阅读8.5分。总分，7分。这是对于高一年级生非常好的模考成绩，不过对我来说，我看到的是8.5和5这两个数字。我立即决定，如果我阅读和听力可以在相当裸考的情况下还能拿8分以上，那我应该将大部分精力放在写作和口语上。<br>决定是这样决定，但是实施起来，我总是觉得没时间。学科和升学这两块占据了我大部分时间，我留给雅思的时间少的可怜。<br>最后，我上了几堂一对一的写作和口语，就浑浑噩噩去考试。结果，7月29日，因为不符合防疫要求，无法参加。<br>8月5日，我终于可以参加雅思考试，但是心中并没有任何激动和喜悦。听力刚开始，我甚至没有反应及时。前两个空根本填不出来，后面的所有题目，除了写作感觉良好，其余的我都无法确定自己是否做好了。<br>8月7日，结果出来，总分依旧是7分。听力7.5分，阅读8分，写作6.5分，口语6分。写作进步了1.5分，但是对我来说仍然不够。听力和阅读比我想象中的也低了很多，口语也很低。这样的成绩，根本不能放上台面。<br>也许，我从一开始就没有对雅思的事情走心。虽然知道很重要，却仍然放弃了努力，以有实力为理由，放任自己偷懒，这样的我，其实是在辜负我的实力。也许那天也有运气和天气作祟的原因，但这些理由，都是心证。在法庭上，真正重要的，只有物证，而我的成绩，就是唯一的物证。我的成绩，无论如何，都是在证明着，我没有尽全力，我没有付出和我同龄人一样多的努力。<br>对于整个高一学期，我的标化并不完美。并没有达到我的期望。但是，我会在高二开学之前，在这个暑假完成第二次雅思考试。</p><p>2022年8月12日，我完成了第二次雅思考试。<br>美中不足的是，小分里只要有一个多加0.5就可以总分8分了，但是我还是有了一个说得过去的成绩。总分7.5分，听力和阅读双双8.5，写作出乎意料的7，口语6.5。口语当时是下午，一进考场脑子就一片空白，没想到竟然还比第一次高。<br>第二次考试之前，我是真的认真刷了题。我发现用电脑模拟机考的时候，我总是忍不住去划去看别的东西。 ，我就拿我几乎从没动过的雅思真题纸制刷。然后阅读认真写了3套，听力认真写了2套，找了点自我安慰就去考试了。</p><p>经过复议，我的雅思成绩到了8分总分。至今我还记得，那天我在经济社教完课之后，和学弟聊天，学弟提到“雅思7分太难拿了”，我还心里赞同。结果，一到家发现雅思成绩复议成功了，写作到了7.5分。虽然口语还在6.5分，但我觉得它没有把我的口语分数拉到6分我就已经很感激了。这里也要感谢《顾家北手把手教你雅思写作》，我考前一直看的都是这本书。</p><h1 id="学科"><a href="#学科" class="headerlink" title="学科"></a>学科</h1><p><strong>时间总占比：30%</strong><br>两学期三好学生，一学期优秀学生干部。<br>其余我会按学科分别进行阐述。我就高一学科表现和IGCSE成绩谈。<br>其实总体来说，我的IGCSE考得并没有想象中的好。尤其是经济物理和进阶数学，原本可以考得更高些的。但是化学成功逆袭还是一个大惊喜。<br><a href="https://postimg.cc/4mpw1YDb"><img src="https://i.postimg.cc/m25qBMVq/Wechat-IMG839.jpg" alt="Wechat-IMG839.jpg"></a></p><h2 id="ESL"><a href="#ESL" class="headerlink" title="ESL"></a>ESL</h2><p>IGCSE A+<br>开学摸底考170分，A等。学期结束，180分，A+等。全年A+。<br>两次月考作文满分。<br>学科优秀奖。<br>就是跟着校内老师按部就班上课、写作业，早读的时候认真看英文书。并没有什么感想。唯一比较可惜的是，下学期我们的ESL老师就离开了。<br>最后ESL也考了92，算是对自己一个学期坚持不骄不躁的答复。</p><h2 id="CS"><a href="#CS" class="headerlink" title="CS"></a>CS</h2><p>全年A+。<br> CS对我没有很大的难度。初级编程只要听课，就能写得有模有样。其他理论知识，因为英语比较好，理解起来也没有什么问题，考前背一下就能用瞬时记忆过。<br> 但是因为我听说CS高级编程非常痛苦，而且我想将大部分时间花在业余生活上，我高二并没有选CS。虽然如此，我对CS仍然有很大的兴趣和热情。甚至我高二准备创建的社团语言学社也和CS有一定的关联。</p><h2 id="经济"><a href="#经济" class="headerlink" title="经济"></a>经济</h2><p>IGCSE A<br>全年A，两次A+。<br>学科优秀奖。<br>虽然暂定的专业方向和经济有关，但是和CS比起来，我在经济方面其实没有多少天赋。所以，提起CS的时候，往往我都是以“有点意思“的感受接触它，几乎把它当成了一个只是学得比较好的兴趣爱好，而面对经济时我的想法就是“这是我的本职工作”。<br>误打误撞参加了NEC的DR级别后，又连续参加了许多经济比赛，我是非常清楚自己在经济方面的能力的。其实，纯经济对我来说还是比较简单的，尤其是宏观，但是商业管理我想因为从来没有类似的经验显得非常艰难。好在，学校的经济教的只是经济而已。<br>我们的外教上课时，有时问了问题没有人回答，我就会试着回答一下。每堂课我都有积极参与，虽然大部分知识我已经预习过了，但是我总是担心会有小点漏掉。<br>经济考试中，我的努力和成绩总是成正比。因为和不怎么费力的CS一对比，我就发现我的经济天赋为0，我只能通过努力将“我的本职工作”做好。但这些努力和我在化学上的努力比起来，又显得九牛一毛了。<br>结果IG成绩出来，发现经济考崩了。只拿了88分，是所有学科里考得最差的，我的学科优秀奖此时就像是在讽刺我一样。这也告诉了我一个道理，就是永远不能小瞧任何一门学科，因为可能你的实力并没有你想象的那么强。</p><h2 id="化学"><a href="#化学" class="headerlink" title="化学"></a>化学</h2><p>IGCSE A+<br>全年A，期末B。<br>我的化学从开学就很差。现在依旧很差。<br>这其中也有初中的原因，我在初三化学就是一个短板。到了高中，基础本就薄弱的我，没有重视化学，就导致了化学成绩一落再落千丈。<br>在化学上花的时间是最多的，但是无奈每次都考不好。每次背完知识点，这一次考试记得下一次就忘了，关于各种命名也分不清楚，分析完了错题发现基础差是真的硬伤。<br>我知道我考化学模考是B了之后，我上网找了好多真题，然后一张张打印，每天都带到学校刷，到最后光是paper 4叠在一起就有4厘米厚，还有paper 2和paper 6也超厚。我第一次做paper 4，就拿了40/80分，有机化学的部分根本不会，因为有机化学是网课上的，我就什么都不记得，我就只好一道题一道题的上网搜。搜不到我只能再搜，翻课本，然后下一张卷子又有新的漏洞…我不喜欢背诵，但是为了化学考好我只好把我错过的答案都试着背下来…那些我背不下来的我就不停念，然后过几天再背一次…还好化学提分比较快，它有一些题型都是常考的，要答的也就那些关键词…一直到第三张，我就到了60/80分，但是我们班大佬都是75分以上…越到后面提分越难，有的时候我的分数都没有之前高，小漏洞也越来越多…最后几张卷子我稳到70分我就放弃继续提分了…<br>最后拿到了93分，甚至比物理还高一分，感动我。不到IGCSE成绩出来，我都不敢把这些刷过的题扔掉，因为我担心成绩出来之后明年还要重考。我现在就很感谢考前努力的自己，其实考前看着刷出来的分数一点点往上走也是一种快乐，似乎背诵什么的都是值得的。</p><blockquote><p>“你只管努力，剩下的交给时间。“<br><a href="https://postimg.cc/6748dvSB"><img src="https://i.postimg.cc/VNDXP9W0/Wechat-IMG1233.jpg" alt="Wechat-IMG1233.jpg"></a><br>上图中的大本子到后来还扩充了几套卷子，弄得只能用铁的大环扣。</p></blockquote><h2 id="物理"><a href="#物理" class="headerlink" title="物理"></a>物理</h2><p> IGCSE A+<br>全年A。<br>物理中等水平。其实我物理基础还行，主要是初中物理老师教得好。那个时候，我们老师常常念叨“思维”“一点两路”云云，让我到了高中看到课本也能想起他曾经说过的那些教诲。<br>我也有担心物理会成为我的短板，最后拿不到A+。为此我也刷过很多套题，大约是化学的一半。遇到不会的题目，就看答案，翻书，问同学。这里感谢我的一位初中同学，不厌其烦地回答了我假期里遇到的不会的在翻译过后的题目，甚至自己不会的时候还会上网帮我找解答；和我的同桌，他早早卷完让他看上去就像一个人型pastpaper网。</p><h2 id="数学"><a href="#数学" class="headerlink" title="数学"></a>数学</h2><p> IGCSE A+<br> 两门都是A+。E数没什么好说的，比较简单，所以我就考前看了一下书，把初中没学过的挑出来背，然后做了几套卷子，掌握了几条易错题的套路，就轻装上阵了。<br> A数相对来说，到了考前比较头疼。因为一开学我对数学适应良好，再加上我初中数学不差，还有个擅长数学的师父，我到后来对数学的态度就有些敷衍。直到我发现我无法再做出课堂习题的时候，我才开始重视数学。同样的思路，我把2022-2019的数学题都做了。从这些卷子里，我发现所有题目都有套路，只要做对那些经典题，基本上不会拿低分。为此我把那些经典题会考的考点全在书上看了很多遍。IGCSE的数学相对来说还是比较简单的，虽然考得比较广，但是题目都有原型，也不是非常难做。</p><p> English Version(machine translation):</p><h1 id="IELTS"><a href="#IELTS" class="headerlink" title="IELTS"></a>IELTS</h1><p><strong>Total time proportion: 10%</strong><br>As soon as the school begins, I got a grade of 170 in ESL. I didn’t spend much effort in English. Knowing the reason why the ambassador failed, I did not relax, but I still took the IELTS class.<br>However, because of my confidence in my English ability, I didn’t do much IELTS Practice. Compared with the students who are also preparing for IELTS, especially those who are serious peers who sign in for self-study and brush questions every morning during the holidays, I can not even exceed their practice amount in one day.<br>With the feeling of being exposed, I went to take a model test in February. As a result, I only got 5 points in writing and 6.5 points in speaking. However, I got 8 points for listening and 8.5 points for reading. Total score: 7 points. This is a very good model test result for freshmen, but for me, I see the numbers 8.5 and 5. I immediately decided that if I could get more than 8 points in the reading and listening tests, I should focus most of my energy on writing and speaking.<br>The decision was made in this way, but when it was implemented, I always felt that there was no time. The subject and the entrance examination occupy most of my time, and I leave little time for IELTS.<br>Finally, I had several one-on-one writing and oral lessons, so I went to the exam in a muddle. As a result, on July 29, I was unable to participate because I did not meet the epidemic prevention requirements.<br>On August 5, I finally took the IELTS test, but there was no excitement or joy in my heart. At the beginning of hearing, I didn’t even respond in time. I can’t fill in the first two blanks at all. I can’t be sure whether I have done well in the rest of the questions except that I feel good about writing.<br>On August 7, the result came out, and the total score was still 7 points. 7.5 points for listening, 8 points for reading, 6.5 points for writing and 6 points for speaking. My writing has improved by 1.5 points, but it is still not enough for me. Listening and reading are much lower than I expected, and oral English is also very low. Such achievements can not be put on the table at all.<br>Perhaps, I haven’t been distracted by IELTS from the beginning. Although I know that it is important, I still give up my efforts and let myself be lazy on the ground of strength. In fact, I am living up to my strength. Maybe there were also reasons for luck and weather that day, but these reasons are all psychological evidence. In court, only material evidence is really important, and my achievements are the only material evidence. My achievements, in any case, are proof that I did not do my best, and I did not pay as much effort as my peers.<br>For the whole semester of senior high school, my standardization is not perfect. It didn’t meet my expectations. However, I will finish the second IELTS test this summer before the beginning of the second year of senior high school.<br>On August 12, 2022, I completed the second IELTS test.<br>The fly in the ointment is that as long as there is one small score plus 0.5, I can get a total score of 8 points, but I still have a fair score. The total score is 7.5, the listening and reading are both 8.5, the writing is unexpected 7, and the oral is 6.5. Oral English was in the afternoon. Once I entered the examination room, my mind was blank. I didn’t expect it was higher than the first time.<br>Before the second exam, I really brushed the questions carefully. I find that when I take a computer-based test, I can’t help but cross over to see other things, I took the paper brush of IELTS that I almost never touched. Then I wrote 3 sets of reading carefully and 2 sets of listening carefully. I found some comfort and went to the test.</p><h1 id="IGCSE"><a href="#IGCSE" class="headerlink" title="IGCSE"></a>IGCSE</h1><p><strong>Total time proportion: 30%</strong><br>Two semesters of three good students, one semester of outstanding student cadres.<br>I will explain the rest by discipline. I’d like to talk about the academic performance and IGCSE scores of senior one.<br>In fact, on the whole, my IGCSE test was not as good as expected. In particular, economic physics and advanced mathematics could have been better. But the successful counter attack of chemistry is still a big surprise.<br><a href="https://postimg.cc/4mpw1YDb"><img src="https://i.postimg.cc/m25qBMVq/Wechat-IMG839.jpg" alt="Wechat-IMG839.jpg"></a></p><h2 id="ESL-1"><a href="#ESL-1" class="headerlink" title="ESL"></a>ESL</h2><p>IGCSE A+<br>170 points in the opening examination, a grade. End of term, 180 points, a +. Annual a +.<br>I got full marks in the two monthly exams.<br>Discipline Excellence Award.<br>It is to follow the teachers in the school to take classes and write homework step by step, and carefully read English books when reading in the morning. I don’t have any feelings. The only pity is that our ESL teacher will leave next semester.<br>Finally, I also got 92 in ESL, which is a reply to my one semester insistence on not being arrogant and impetuous.</p><h2 id="CS-1"><a href="#CS-1" class="headerlink" title="CS"></a>CS</h2><p>Annual a +.<br>CS is not very difficult for me. As long as you listen to the class, you can write the basic programming in a good way. Other theoretical knowledge, because my English is better, there is no problem in understanding it. I can memorize it immediately before the test.<br>But because I heard that CS advanced programming is very painful, and I want to spend most of my time in my spare time, I didn’t choose CS in my senior two. Nevertheless, I still have great interest and enthusiasm for CS. Even the community language society that I plan to establish in my second year of senior high school is related to CS.</p><h2 id="Economics"><a href="#Economics" class="headerlink" title="Economics"></a>Economics</h2><p>IGCSE A<br>A in the whole year and a + twice.<br>Discipline Excellence Award.<br>Although the tentative professional direction is related to economics, compared with CS, I actually have little talent in economics. Therefore, when I talk about CS, I always contact it with the feeling of “a little interesting”. I almost regard it as a hobby that I have learned well. When I face the economy, I think that “this is my job”.<br>After taking part in the Dr level of NEC by mistake, I have participated in many economic competitions in succession. I am very clear about my economic ability. In fact, the pure economy is relatively simple for me, especially the macro economy, but I think business management is very difficult because I have never had similar experience. Fortunately, the school’s economics only teaches economics.<br>When our foreign teachers ask questions in class and no one answers them, I will try to answer them. I have actively participated in every class. Although I have previewed most of the knowledge, I am always worried that a little bit will be missed.<br>In the economic examination, my efforts are always proportional to my grades. Because I found that my economic talent is 0 when compared with CS, which is not very laborious, I can only do my job well through hard work. However, compared with my efforts in chemistry, these efforts are a drop in the bucket.<br>As a result, the Ig scores came out and it was found that the economy had failed. I only got 88 points, which was the worst in all subjects. At this time, my academic excellence award seemed to satirize me. This also tells me a truth, that is, never underestimate any subject, because your strength may not be as strong as you think.</p><h2 id="Chemistry"><a href="#Chemistry" class="headerlink" title="Chemistry"></a>Chemistry</h2><p>IGCSE A+<br>A in the whole year and B at the end of the period.<br>My chemistry has been poor since the beginning of school. It’s still very bad.<br>There are also junior high school reasons. I was a short board in chemistry in junior high school. In high school, I had a weak foundation and did not pay attention to chemistry, which led to a drop in chemistry scores.<br>I spent the most time on chemistry, but I couldn’t do well every time. Every time I memorize the knowledge points, I remember this exam and forget the next time. I can’t distinguish the names clearly. After analyzing the wrong questions, I find that the poor foundation is really a hard injury.<br>I know that after I got a B in the chemistry model test, I searched for many real questions on the Internet, and then printed them one by one. I took them to the school every day to brush them. At the end of the day, paper 4 alone was 4 cm thick, and paper 2 and paper 6 were also too thick. The first time I did paper 4, I got 40 / 80 points. I can’t do organic chemistry at all. Because organic chemistry is an online class, I can’t remember anything. So I have to search the Internet one by one. If I can’t find it, I can only search again, turn to the textbook, and then the next paper has new loopholes… I don’t like reciting, but in order to do well in the chemistry test, I have to try to memorize all the answers I missed… I don’t stop reciting those that I can’t memorize, and then recite them again in a few days… Fortunately, chemistry scores are faster, and some of the questions are often tested, and the key words to be answered… Until the third page, I reached 60 / 80 points, But our class leaders are all above 75 points… The more they get to the back, the more difficult it is to raise points. Sometimes my scores are not as high as before, and there are more and more small loopholes… The last few papers are stable to 70 points, so I give up raising points<br>Finally, I got 93 points, even one point higher than physics, which moved me. Before the IGCSE scores come out, I dare not throw away these brushed questions, because I am afraid that I will have to retake the exam next year after the results come out. I’m very grateful for my efforts before the exam. In fact, it’s a pleasure to watch the scores brush up before the exam. It seems that it’s worth reciting.</p><blockquote><p>“Just try hard and leave the rest to time“<br><a href="https://postimg.cc/6748dvSB"><img src="https://i.postimg.cc/VNDXP9W0/Wechat-IMG1233.jpg" alt="Wechat-IMG1233.jpg"></a><br>The large book in the above figure has been expanded with several sets of papers, so that only large iron rings can be used.</p></blockquote><h2 id="Physics"><a href="#Physics" class="headerlink" title="Physics"></a>Physics</h2><p>IGCSE A+<br>All year round a.<br>Physics is medium. In fact, my physical foundation is OK, mainly because my junior high school physics teacher taught me well. At that time, our teacher often talked about “thinking” and “one point, two ways”, so that when I saw the textbooks in high school, I could think of the teachings he once said.<br>I’m also worried that physics will become my weakness and I won’t get a +. For this reason, I have also brushed many sets of questions, about half that of chemistry. When you encounter a problem that you can’t, you can read the answer, turn the book, and ask your classmates. Here, I would like to thank one of my junior high school classmates for taking the trouble to answer the questions that I met during my vacation after translation, and even for helping me find answers on the Internet when I can’t; With my deskmate, he finished rolling early so that he looked like a man-made pastpaper net.</p><h2 id="Mathematics"><a href="#Mathematics" class="headerlink" title="Mathematics"></a>Mathematics</h2><p>IGCSE A+<br>Both doors are a +. There is nothing to say about E-number, which is quite simple. So I read a book before the test, picked out the ones I didn’t learn in junior high school, memorized them, and then made several sets of papers. After mastering several sets of easy to make mistakes, I went to the battle light.<br>A: relatively speaking, I have a headache before the exam. Because I had a good adaptation to mathematics at the beginning of school, and my junior high school mathematics was not bad, and there was a master who was good at mathematics, I had a perfunctory attitude towards mathematics. It wasn’t until I found that I couldn’t do class exercises that I began to pay attention to mathematics. In the same way, I did all the math problems from 2022 to 2019. From these papers, I found that all the questions have routines. As long as I do the classic questions correctly, I won’t get low scores. For this reason, I have read many times in the book all the examination points of the classic questions. The mathematics of IGCSE is relatively simple. Although the test is relatively wide, the questions have prototypes and are not very difficult to do.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">IELTS:7.5 IGCSE:5A*1A</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="IGCSE" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/categories/IGCSE/"/>
    
    <category term="Life" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/categories/IGCSE/Life/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Experience" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Experience/"/>
    
    <category term="Summary" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Summary/"/>
    
    <category term="Study Tips" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/Study-Tips/"/>
    
    <category term="IELTS" scheme="https://olivezq.github.io/tags/IELTS/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
